<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>figma &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/figma/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 04:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>figma &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>My UX Design Toolbox</title>
		<link>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/</link>
					<comments>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 09:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe after effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe xd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design Toolbelts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UX Design Tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just like carpenters rely on different tools for different tasks, so do UX designers. Start adding some tools to your digital toolbox and explore a few of the most popular [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just like carpenters rely on different tools for different tasks, so do UX designers. Start adding some tools to your digital toolbox and explore a few of the most popular programs that you might use as an entry-level UX designer.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/9RMZiVf.png" alt="A person with long hair stands in front of toolbox holding a laptop. Text above reads wireframing and prototyping tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 1"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 5</figcaption></figure>



<p>Early in your UX design career, you’ll likely spend a lot of time creating wireframes and prototypes.</p>



<ul><li>A <strong>wireframe</strong> is an outline or a sketch of a product or a screen. Wireframes help designers figure out how a page is arranged, where each piece of a product fits in with the others, and how users will likely interact with the product.</li><li>A <strong>prototype</strong> is an early model of a product that demonstrates functionality.</li></ul>



<p>You’ll learn much more about wireframes and prototypes, and create your own, as you progress through this certificate program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are tons of digital tools available to help you design wireframes and prototypes. The most popular tools among them are Figma and Adobe XD due to their availability:</p>



<span id="more-15627"></span>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.figma.com/design/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Figma</u></strong></a> is a widely used, all-in-one wireframing and prototyping tool that allows for real-time collaboration among multiple team members. This makes Figma ideal for designers working remotely and for teams with members in different locations. Figma is versatile and customizable, with plenty of features to speed up the design process. The greatest thing about Figma is its availability. Being a web app, Figma is capable of running on pretty much every computer in existence, regardless of its operating systems (even Linuxes), as long as it is capable of running a modern browser.</li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/xd.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Adobe XD</u></strong></a> is great for editing graphics, building prototypes, and collaborating with other people on your team. It has particularly robust features for tasks that happen during the later stages of UX design, as you get into what we call high-fidelity designs. Unlike Figma which was built on web technologies, Adobe XD is still a traditional desktop application which mean you will need to be running the latest version of either OS X or Windows to be able to use it.</li><li><a href="https://www.sketch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Sketch</u></strong></a> was formerly an extremely popular wireframing and prototyping tool in the UX community. However Sketch can only run on Mac OS X, which means most UX designers will not be able to use it even if they want to (although they recently added a web version to alleviate that somewhat). This couples with the fact that Sketch does not have a free version like Figma or Adobe XD has caused Sketch&#8217;s popularity to crumble in recent years. This was a situation similarly faced by <a href="https://www.framer.com/why-framer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Framer</u></strong></a>, arguably one of the most advanced UX design tools. Framer used to be a paid-only Mac application just like Sketch, but their development team quickly realized such high barrier to entry will severely limit their user base and eventually fade from existence like Sketch. Today Framer is available on both Mac (even the new M1 variant) and Windows, with a free tier similar to Figma.</li></ul>



<p>And of course, there are other tools like UXPin, InVision, MarvelApp that you can discover on your own</p>



<p>Keep in mind that the UX design industry changes often, and so do design tools. Many of the skills we’ll explore as part of this program are transferable, meaning once you know the basics in one tool, like Figma or Adobe XD, that knowledge will transfer to other design tools that look and feel quite similar.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/pUcKZM7.png" alt="A person holding a megaphone stands in front of a toolbox. Text above reads &quot;presentation tools&quot;" title="My UX Design Toolbox 2"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 6</figcaption></figure>



<p>During the early, conceptual phases of the design process, you don’t always need to use tools that were specifically made for UX design. In fact, some designers prefer working within the relative simplicity of presentation programs, especially when they’re creating wireframes. Most presentation tools also have live collaboration features, so team members can interact with each other and collaborate on the designs. Here are three of the most popular presentation tools from Google, Microsoft, and Apple:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://slides.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Slides.com</strong></a> (or <strong><a href="https://slid.es/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://slid.es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">slid.es</a></strong>) is my top choice. It&#8217;s dead simple. It&#8217;s available everywhere. Use it.</li><li><a href="https://workspace.google.com/products/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Google Slides</u></strong></a> is a web-based presentation program included in Google Workspace, Google’s suite of productivity software. Google Slides is free, and anyone with a Google account can create or edit Slides presentations.</li><li><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/powerpoint" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Microsoft PowerPoint</u></strong></a> was one of the first presentation programs created, and it’s still very widely used. PowerPoint is part of the Microsoft 365 program package and comes in both offline and online versions. Although anyone can view a PowerPoint presentation online, you have to own the product to create or edit a presentation.</li><li><a href="https://www.apple.com/keynote/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Keynote</u></strong></a> is Apple’s presentation program, and a lot of people consider its templates to be the most visually appealing. It’s also available both online and offline. Although Keynote was created for Apple devices like Macs and iPads, it can be used on a PC, as well. Similar to PowerPoint, you have to own the product to make edits or create new presentations in Keynote.</li></ul>



<p>In many instances, presentation tools are a matter of preference. Feel free to try out many of them, and pick whichever you feel most comfortable working with!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/flUQ67q.png" alt="A person holding a camera and scissors and standing in front of a toolbox. Text above: image creation and manipulation tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 3"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 7</figcaption></figure>



<p>As you develop your designs, you might need to use tools to create, manipulate, and integrate images and illustrations. Here are two of the most popular image creation and manipulation tools:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/illustrator.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Affinity Designer</u></strong></a> is primarily used for drawing vector images. <strong>Vector images </strong>(or SVGs) are images created using points, curves, lines, and shapes to produce perfectly smooth lines. This makes it easy to edit and resize images in Illustrator. As an entry-level UX designer, you can use Adobe Illustrator to draw prototypes and illustrations for your designs.</li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Affinity Photo</u></strong></a> works primarily with photos, known as raster images. These images are composed of thousands, or even millions, of pixels, the smallest unit of display on a computer screen. While its cousin Illustrator is a better tool for creating an image from scratch, Photoshop has more uses, including image manipulation across file types, saving images for digital publishing, and even presentations.</li></ul>



<p>Now you might be confused with those familiar names. Normally you&#8217;d expect to see Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop filling those slots, and for good reasons. They are decidedly better tools. However Adobe&#8217;s decision to put them in a subscription model had effectively killed them for the smaller independent designers like myself. I&#8217;m not sponsored by them or anything, it&#8217;s just that compare to Adobe, I like Affinity&#8217;s perpetual pricing model MUCH better.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also Gravit Design which was a great project back in the day. It works with both vector and raster images, and it runs on the web! Just like Figma, it can be configured to be used as a desktop application with Electron. Unfortunately it was bought out by Corel, which means it will eventually meet the same fate as Ulead PhotoImpact or JASC Paint Shop Pro. It was a shame really, seeing how it could&#8217;ve overtaken GIMP and Krita as the de facto image editor on Linux.</p>



<p>In all honesty though, most basic image manipulation can already be done in your screen design tool. Figma can handle both SVG Vector and raster images just fine. It can cut, crop, resize, even do basic color correction there. Only use AI and PS if you want to create something more hardcore, because let&#8217;s face it, they are massive resource hogs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/OOjd7BE.png" alt="A person holding a slate while standing in front of a toolbox. Text above reads: animation tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 4"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 8</figcaption></figure>



<p>Creating animations can be a great way to showcase the more interactive elements of your designs. For example, you could create a Graphics Interchange Format (GIF) to demonstrate how a user might interact with the homepage of an app you’re designing. There are many programs that UX designers can use to create animations, but here are a couple to highlight:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://lottiefiles.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Lottie</u></strong></a> is a tool that helps you edit and ship your animations in just a few clicks. Animation files formatted in Lottie, also known as LottieFiles, use less file space on your hard drive since they are code-based. On Lottie, you can also explore animations created by other designers for inspiration or use. </li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/aftereffects.html?sdid=KKQOW&amp;mv=search&amp;kw=test&amp;ef_id=Cj0KCQjwuL_8BRCXARIsAGiC51CSU9gu_SrVG40X-2ClEFnFfKuEKYYQ4kOtlm6F3Y4Kon1hf5z6oSwaAvXLEALw_wcB:G:s&amp;s_kwcid=AL!3085!3!469900475182!e!!g!!adobe%20after%20effects&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwuL_8BRCXARIsAGiC51CSU9gu_SrVG40X-2ClEFnFfKuEKYYQ4kOtlm6F3Y4Kon1hf5z6oSwaAvXLEALw_wcB" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Adobe After Effects</u></strong></a> is often used to add motion graphics and visual effects to designs. For example, UX designers might utilize Adobe After Effects to make text move across the screen or create transitions between pages.</li><li><strong><a href="https://rive.app/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rive.app/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rive.app</a></strong> is a spanking new entry into the market. It is used to create smooth animations. Especially popular among those who&#8217;s looking into developing Flutter applications</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Results are in!</title>
		<link>/2020/12/the-results-are-in/</link>
					<comments>/2020/12/the-results-are-in/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 04:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ui design tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux design tool]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Figma is now the king in interface design industry. It didn&#8217;t just overtake Sketch, it pretty much buried it six feet under. Not only that, it even managed to buried [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1024" height="796" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-1024x796.png" alt="image" class="wp-image-14807" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-1024x796.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-300x233.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-768x597.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-64x50.png 64w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-650x505.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-1000x777.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-50x39.png 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image.png 1341w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" title="The Results are in! 9"><figcaption>The Results are in! 10</figcaption></figure>



<p>Figma is now the king in interface design industry. It didn&#8217;t just overtake Sketch, it pretty much buried it six feet under. Not only that, it even managed to buried other competitors in other category too. Like prototyping (which was pioneered and led by InVision for the longest time) and handoff (something that was typically handled by Zeplin).</p>



<p>Figma&#8217;s lead in almost every single category in the design process is a testament to what the designers truly want: more feature in a single, unified package rather than super specialized tools that focus on a single aspect of the design process.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong though, specialized tools have their uses, and I&#8217;d argue their places are quite indispensable. But they are more useful in large studios with extended work pipelines where there are people dedicated to certain parts of the process.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/12/the-results-are-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Figma UI Recreation Challenge #1: Streamlabs Dashboard</title>
		<link>/2020/04/figma-ui-recreation-challenge-1-streamlabs-dashboard/</link>
					<comments>/2020/04/figma-ui-recreation-challenge-1-streamlabs-dashboard/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freebies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ui freebies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once in a while I&#8217;d come across a screenshot of a cool UI that I think would be relatively simple to recreate in Figma, so I made it a personal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once in a while I&#8217;d come across a screenshot of a cool UI that I think would be relatively simple to recreate in Figma, so I made it a personal challenge to do so. This is not something that I do in my spare time or anything because, quite frankly I don&#8217;t have any spare time anymore. This is more of a distraction to prevent me from going insane between juggling 3 different major projects atm.</p>
<p>I will first start with 2 Streamlabs dashboard screens.</p>
<p><span id="more-6326"></span></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart.png"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-6327 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart.png" alt="Streamlabs Dashboard Chart" width="1280" height="800" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart.png 1280w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-300x188.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-1024x640.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-768x480.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-80x50.png 80w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-650x406.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-1000x625.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-1250x781.png 1250w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-Dashboard-Chart-50x31.png 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" title="Figma UI Recreation Challenge #1: Streamlabs Dashboard 13"></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs.png"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-6328 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs.png" alt="Streamlabs" width="1280" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs.png 1280w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-89x50.png 89w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-650x366.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-1000x563.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Streamlabs-50x28.png 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" title="Figma UI Recreation Challenge #1: Streamlabs Dashboard 14"></a></p>
<p>You can get the file from my Freebies site <a href="https://freebies.namvu.net/figma-freebie-streamlabs-dashboard/">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/04/figma-ui-recreation-challenge-1-streamlabs-dashboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just discovered Figma&#8217;s Smart Animate feature</title>
		<link>/2019/10/just-discovered-figmas-smart-animate-feature/</link>
					<comments>/2019/10/just-discovered-figmas-smart-animate-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 03:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototyping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screen design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ui design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And it&#8217;s fucking amazing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And it&#8217;s fucking amazing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/just-discovered-figmas-smart-animate-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zeplin Desktop client for Linux</title>
		<link>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/</link>
					<comments>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 03:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natifier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[native zeplin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin linux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As mentioned in one of my previous posts, we now have an excellent tool for screen design to work on right there on Linux. But what about design handoff? With [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As mentioned in one of my <a href="/2018/10/30/installing-figma-client-on-deepin-linux-15-7-desktop/">previous posts,</a> we now have an excellent tool for screen design to work on right there on Linux. But what about design handoff? With Figma, normally you have 2 choices for handoff: one is Avocode, the other is Zeplin. Most people would prefer Zeplin since Avocode is a subscription based abomination. But there&#8217;s one problem for Linux screen designer: Zeplin does not have a desktop client for Linux. Now this isn&#8217;t much of an issue like other softwares because they have a webapp, but you can&#8217;t integrate Figma with the webapp, unfortunately.</p>
<p>After looking around, I realize Zeplin, like many other great web-based apps, was built on top of the execellnt ElectronJS framework, that means porting it is fairly trivial. After murking around, I came up with this, let me know if it works:</p>
<h4><a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1aNEzGFXTPJ8d7UGywEUjsK8XWsa9lw71" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Download zeplin-linux-x64.tar.gz</a></h4>
<p>Made with nativefier</p>
<p>So now that we&#8217;ve managed to make desktop client for both Figma and Linux, it should be trivial to integrate them right? Well not really, turns out the folks over at Figma currently only has the integration option enabled for their Windows and Mac client. If you&#8217;re a designer working on Linux right now, and need Figma &amp; Zeplin integration, consider spamming their support blog for this feature. I mean, we did that hard part, creating the desktop clients for them, right? All they need to do now is enable integration between the 2 apps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essential things to get things done in Linux (2019 edition)</title>
		<link>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 04:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gravit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[libreoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietkey linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wps office]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ok I’m gonna give an honest list of the best software to use in each category in MY unbiased experience. What I mean by unbiased is that I will pick [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ok I’m gonna give an honest list of the best software to use in each category in MY unbiased experience. What I mean by unbiased is that I will pick a software base solely on the overall user experience that it provides (functionality AND aesthetic), REGARDLESS of whether it’s Free software or not. Most other list will either be sponsored or heavily biased toward free software, and since there’s only one or two decent software in each category, you’ll end up seeing pretty much the same list over and over again, year in and year out.</p>
<p>It’s not that I don’t support free software, quite the contrary I’m actually a huge supporter of free software (why else would a graphic designer like me use Linux as his primary working platform). But I’m also aware that for a platform like Linux to gain traction in the end-user market, it needs support from software developers. Yes, all of them, even proprietary software. After all, you can only reasonably expect a program to function correctly if the developer behind it has the incentive to make it better.</p>
<p>Onto the list, my choices are based on the following criterias: <strong><b>function</b></strong>, <strong><b>aesthetic</b></strong>, and <strong><b>performance</b></strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><b>Function </b></strong>means it has to get the thing it was designed for done, that’s the baseline.</li>
<li><strong><b>Aesthetic </b></strong>means it has to have a well designed interface. This is, for the longest time, the weakest point in most opensource software. Obviously it’s not as important as Function but IMO still a far more important aspect to software than most people give it credit for. A well design UI/UX will boost your productivity by a wide margin.</li>
<li><strong><b>Performance </b></strong>means the software have to perform at its best on Linux, meaning no emulated Windows or OS X App, VMs are out of the table also. That doesn’t mean the app have to be native, mind you. It’s 2018, I will also gladly choose app created with web technologies like Figma or Vectr, granted that it runs consistently on Linux just as it does on any other platform.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Here we go</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best Linux Distro: Deepin OS</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will tell you about Ubuntu, Mint or Fedora</em></p>
<p>I’ve used quite a lot of different distros in my time. Off the top of my head, I’ve used Ubuntu, Mint, elementaryOS, Majaro, Arch, Fedora, Zorin. You can see there’s no Gentoo, Red Hat or CentOS in my line up. That’s because I’m not a power Linux user, I only choose distros that boast userfriendliness, aimed at the end user, with pretty interfaces. And judging by the criterias, Deepin OS takes the trophy.</p>
<p>I remember some 15-16 years ago, when Vietkey Linux &#8211; the first ‘Vietnamese’ operating system hit the mass. Yes it was simply a reskin of Red Hat, with little change under the hood, but it got me into liking the platform. Back then, the UI of Linux in general, compares to its contemporary counterpart Windows XP, was nothing short of a massive pile of steaming garbage. And then Ubuntu came along with its sweet streamlined interface and Compiz-powered effects. I was completely blown away.</p>
<p>Fast forward 16 years later, when pretty much everything on the market more or less has a good UI, I didn’t expect to get that sensation again, but then I did, when I installed Deepin OS.</p>
<p>To be honest, my expectation for the distro was low, mostly due to my previous experience with a Chinese distro called Red Flag Linux, yes I do realize the irony of the name. But the Deepin experience wasn’t like Red Flag, but more like MIUI. It’s clean, it’s fresh, packed with little touches that indicates there was involvement from real UI/UX/IxD designers. Unlike most Chinese product, Deepin didn’t feel like a copied and pasted product, because it’s not. The overall user experience is very pleasant (except for the setting sidebar, I mean, who brilliant UX designer was it that think people want the settings they’re changing to disappear everytime they click outside the window?)</p>
<p>Overall. I rate this a 10/10, the first time I ever rate a distro this high. Meaning this is a mature product, complete and ready to compete with the likes of Windows and Mac. It’s currently my production platform.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best Office Suite: WPS Office</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will tell you about OpenOffice and LibreOffice.</em></p>
<p>Yet another software from China, by now some people must be think I might be a commie. Well I actually am, but that’s not why I choose WPS Office. I choose it simply because it is THE best office suite for Linux, in every way. LibreOffice is based on OpenOffice, this massive pile of Java code that is both fugly and sluggish. WPS on the other hand is responsive, good looking, has great compatibility (it saves as microsoft file format instead of its own), AND portability (1GB of cloud storage means you can access your file anywhere, anytime instead of worrying about forgetting to hit Ctrl-S.</p>
<p>Overall, the only reason why WPS hadn’t dominate the Linux office world yet is because a lot of people still use Office for idealistic reasons rather than focusing on productivity reason (and also, many people don’t trust Chinese softwares, much less storing sensitive files on their cloud). They are all valid reason, but for me, WPS is the office suite of choice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best raster graphic editor: Krita</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will say it’s the GIMP</em></p>
<p>As one of the longest supporter of the GNU Image Manipulation Program, it makes me sad that the software had lagged so far behind. For a while, it was considered a Photoshop ‘alternative’, and some still calls it that, but we all know that’s not the case anymore. While the offering from Adobe has received a crapton of new features over the years due to their massive resources, our beloved GIMP still look and feel like the same guy we use 10 years ago. Even the image editor that comes with K-Office: Krita beat the GIMP in every aspects. Maybe it’s time we let it rest.</p>
<p>Krita on the other hands had seen massive improvements over the years. It now has the UI of a professional image editor, something that the GIMP couldn’t accomplished after decades of development.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best vector graphic editor: Gravit Designer</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will say it’s Inkscape</em></p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, Inkscape is a heavy contender. The gap between Inkscape and AI is far smaller than the gap between GIMP and PS. And yet I still have to choose a web based app over it due to its ease of use, its beautiful aesthetic, and portability (storing files on the cloud ftw!)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best screen design tool: Figma</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will have no idea what it is.</em></p>
<p>Screen design tool is a new software segment, one that didn’t exist just a few years ago. I myself didn’t even know of their existence until Adobe released their Adobe XD a few years ago. Yes I know that was already pretty late since Adobe themselves were late to the game, XD hit the market as a response to Sketch’s popularity. Like I said in a previous blog post, I believe that despite its massive popularity, Sketch’s days are numbered, killed by free cross-platform tools like Adobe XD and Figma.</p>
<p>Figma is not the best screen design tool on Linux, nor it is the best screen design tool on the web. It is THE best screen design tool, across all platform, period. Everything you do, you do directly on the cloud, you don’t ever have to worry about hitting Ctrl+S ever again!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Best 3D software package</strong></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Sketch will die in 2019</title>
		<link>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe xd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comparison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namvu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screen design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma. If you’re a screen designer of any calibre, surely you’ve heard of at least one of these tools. They’re currently the 3 biggest players in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma. If you’re a screen designer of any calibre, surely you’ve heard of at least one of these tools. They’re currently the 3 biggest players in the screen design tool arena.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sketch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Features: being the oldest tool means it has a very healthy ecosystem with a plethora of plugins</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Cons</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Availability: being a Mac exclusive app means it’s only a matter of time before it’s erased from the market.</p>
<p>&#8211; Speed: Sketch is snappy when it comes to opening a file, but viewport stability decreases drastically when navigating around a large project.</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: like every other Mac apps, this shit cost money. If you’re a solo creator, this app is currently more expensive than the other 2 combined times infinity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Adobe XD:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Adobe Ecosystem: being tied to the biggest creativity toolset on the market is a huge!</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: it used to cost money, but it’s free now (undoubted in an effort to accelerate the construction of Sketch’s coffin)</p>
<p>&#8211; Availability: Adobe has a bit more advantage over Sketch in term of platform availability, given that it works on both Windows and OS X. A common misconception is that the majority of the design community works on OS X, that’s only true in North America and Europe. If you count globally, you’ll see that most companies operating in the outsourcing sector (India, APAC) still uses Windows as the primary operating system. Some statistics currently put Sketch at over 70% dominance, but if you count the actual product output (which is huge in the outsourcing sector), I’d suspect that number would drop to somewhere around 30%.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Cons</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Adobe Ecosystem: yes, this is both a pro and con for this nifty little app. Being part of a giant company like Adobe certainly has its perk, while we know Adobe has the resources needed to make Adobe a thing, whether or not those resources are allocated correctly is a different story. We all know there’s very little innovation left going on at Adobe, having dominated the market for so long. They’ve also killed off fantastic tools like Freehand and (gasp!) Fireworks!</p>
<p>&#8211; Availability consistency: apart from the fact that there’s still no client on Linux (which is not a huge deal, I say this as a designer who uses Linux, I know there’s not that many of us).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Figma:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Availability: Figma is the champion when it comes to platform availability. This tool is built with WebGL, with desktop wrapper for desktop use (like Slack). That means it works everywhere as long as you have a web browser (currently it’s THE screen designer of choice for designer working in Linux)</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: if you’re a solo creator, it’s completely free, there’s no limit on the number of project you can have in your account. They only charge if you want to add more than 2 editors to your project, which is completely reasonable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
