<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>UX Design &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/ux-design/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:58:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>UX Design &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shout out to Portainer.io for the UI facelift</title>
		<link>/2022/09/shout-out-to-portainer-io-for-the-ui-facelift/</link>
					<comments>/2022/09/shout-out-to-portainer-io-for-the-ui-facelift/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As an avid Portainer user and a UI designer, I just want to give a shout out to whoever worked on Portainer 2.15&#8217;s new UI facelift. They truly did a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As an avid Portainer user and a UI designer, I just want to give a shout out to whoever worked on Portainer 2.15&#8217;s new UI facelift. They truly did a great job. Not only does it LOOK better, it actually addresses some of the minor annoyance that existed in the old UI.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="800" height="450" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/2.15-ui-home-comparison.gif" alt="2.15 ui home comparison" class="wp-image-21872" title="Shout out to Portainer.io for the UI facelift 1"><figcaption>Environment Page comparison</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="800" height="450" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/2.15-ui-addregistry-comparison.gif" alt="2.15 ui addregistry comparison" class="wp-image-21873" title="Shout out to Portainer.io for the UI facelift 2"><figcaption>Registry Page comparison</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>



<p>Now to be clear, the old UI wasn&#8217;t trash or anything, it was pretty okay, but it wasn&#8217;t GREAT. And while it didn&#8217;t affect the way Portainer works, there were some minor visual bugs that bother UI designers and/or hardcore nitpicking perfectionists, and I just happen to be both.</p>



<p>Take the App Templates page for example. In the old version, there were no constraints set for the app icons, and since they come in all shapes and sizes, they often get stretched and distorted beyond recognition, making the page looking very amateurish.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s no longer the case</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="515" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-1024x515.png" alt="image" class="wp-image-21871" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-1024x515.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-300x151.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-768x386.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-1536x772.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-99x50.png 99w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-650x327.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-1000x503.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image-50x25.png 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/image.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" title="Shout out to Portainer.io for the UI facelift 3"><figcaption>Great job, Portainer UI designer</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/09/shout-out-to-portainer-io-for-the-ui-facelift/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>About UX Research</title>
		<link>/2022/04/about-ux-research/</link>
					<comments>/2022/04/about-ux-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 09:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are two key parts to every UX design project: conducting research to learn about the users you’re designing for, and gathering feedback about their perspectives. UX design is all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There are two key parts to every UX design project: conducting research to learn about the users you’re designing for, and gathering feedback about their perspectives. UX design is all about putting the user first, and research helps designers understand those users.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>UX research</strong> focuses on understanding user behaviors, needs, and motivations through observation and feedback. Your product design should be built upon research and facts, not assumptions. UX research aligns what you, as the designer, <em>think</em> the user needs with what the user <em>actually</em> needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember the product development life cycle from an earlier course of the program? The <strong>product development life cycle</strong> has five stages — brainstorm, define, design, test, and launch — that take an idea for an app, website, or product to its launch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s check out how research fits into the product development life cycle.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/JHw9ulJ.png" alt="JHw9ulJ" title="About UX Research 4"><figcaption>About UX Research 8</figcaption></figure>



<span id="more-21750"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/PlnIgEj.png" alt="icon of a person holding a magnifying glass; text reads: foundational research" title="About UX Research 5"><figcaption>About UX Research 9</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Foundational research</strong> is always done <em>before</em> you start designing. Within the product development life cycle, foundational research happens during the brainstorm stage (stage one) to help you empathize with users, understand their needs, and inspire new design directions. During this stage, you will also make personas and user stories, which you&#8217;ll learn about soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In foundational research, your goal is to figure out what the user needs and how to address those needs with your product. Strong foundational research can contradict your personal perspective on what a good solution might be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Questions you might consider during foundational research include:</p>



<ul><li>What should we build?</li><li>What are the user’s problems?</li><li>How can we solve those problems?</li><li>Am I aware of my own biases, and am I able to filter them as I do research?</li></ul>



<p>There are lots of research methods for conducting foundational research, but many of them are based on observations. Common foundational research methods include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Interviews:</strong> A research method used to collect in-depth information on people&#8217;s opinions, thoughts, experiences, and feelings. You’ll often conduct interviews of your target users themselves.</li><li><strong>Surveys:</strong> An activity where many people are asked the same questions in order to understand what most people think about a product.</li><li><strong>Focus groups:</strong> A small group of people whose reactions are studied. For example, your focus group might bring together eight users to discuss their perspectives about new features in your design. A focus group is usually run by a moderator who guides the group on a certain topic of conversation.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Competitive audit:</strong> An overview of your competitors’ strengths and weaknesses. You&#8217;ll conduct your own competitive audit later in the course, so you will understand this research method well!&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Field studies:</strong> Research activities that take place in the user&#8217;s context or personal environment, rather than in an office or lab.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Diary studies:</strong> A research method used to collect qualitative data about user behaviors, activities, and experiences over time. Often, a user will log, or diary, about their daily activities and provide information about their behaviors and needs, which can help inform your designs.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/X3SCz9i.png" alt="icon of a profile of a head with tools and icons coming out of the top; text reads: design research" title="About UX Research 6"><figcaption>About UX Research 10</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Design research</strong> is done <em>while</em> you design. Within the product development lifecycle, design research happens during the design stage (stage three) to help inform your designs, to fit the needs of users, and to reduce risk. Each time you create a new version of your design, new research should be done to evaluate what works well and what needs to be changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In design research, your goal is to answer the question: How should we build it?</p>



<p>The amount of design research you conduct will vary depending on where you work and what you’re building. The most common method used to conduct design research is a <strong>usability study</strong>, which is a technique to evaluate a product by testing it on users. The goal of usability studies is to identify pain points that the user experiences with your prototypes, so the issues can be fixed before the product launches. You’ll conduct your own usability study in the next course of this certificate program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additional research methods that might be used to conduct design research include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>A/B testing</strong>: A research method that evaluates and compares two different aspects of a product to discover which of them is most effective. For example, you might have users evaluate two layouts for the homepage of your app to find out which layout is more effective.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Cafe or guerrilla studies:</strong> A research method where user feedback is gathered by taking a design or prototype into the public domain and asking passersby for their thoughts. For example, you might sit in a local coffee shop and ask customers if they would be willing to test your app design for a couple of minutes and provide feedback.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Card sorting: </strong>A research method that instructs study participants to sort individual labels written on notecards into categories that make sense to them. This type of research is largely used to figure out the information architecture of your project, which we’ll discuss in the next course of the program — Course 3: Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Designs.</li><li><strong>Intercepts: </strong>A research method that gathers on-site feedback from users as they engage in the activities being researched. Intercepts are often conducted in the field, so this type of research is often considered a subset of field research. An intercept study can provide quick, high-level feedback.</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/htAJImN.png" alt="icon of a rocket ship in front of a laptop screen; text reads: post-launch research" title="About UX Research 7"><figcaption>About UX Research 11</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Post-launch research</strong> is done <em>after</em> the design is complete and your product has launched. Within the product development life cycle, post-launch research happens after the launch stage (stage five) to help validate that the product is meeting user needs through established metrics.</p>



<p>In post-launch research, your goal is to answer the question: Did we succeed? This research will tell you how your final product is performing based on established metrics, such as adoption, usage, user satisfaction, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should use research methods that give insight into what the user thinks of your product and if their experience using your product aligns with how you intended it to function. Research methods you might use to conduct post-launch research include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>A/B testing</strong></li><li><strong>Usability studies</strong></li><li><strong>Surveys</strong></li><li><strong>Logs analysis:</strong> A research method used to evaluate recordings of users while they interact with your design, tools, etc.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The key to a user-focused product: Research</h2>



<p>Research is crucial to creating a product that satisfies users. As an entry-level designer, it might be tempting to assume what the user needs based on your own experience, but as you know: The user comes first. Always make sure that your opinions are backed up by your research. You should get feedback from your users before, during, and after you design!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/04/about-ux-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conducting User Interviews</title>
		<link>/2021/07/conducing-user-interviews/</link>
					<comments>/2021/07/conducing-user-interviews/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 03:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a UX designer, you&#8217;ll always focus on the user and the experience they’ll have with the product you’re designing. In this course, you’ll learn about the first phase of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a UX designer, you&#8217;ll always focus on the user and the experience they’ll have with the product you’re designing. In this course, you’ll learn about the first phase of the design process, empathizing with users, which is critical when it comes to creating a great user experience. In order to empathize with users and understand their pain points, you&#8217;ll need to conduct interviews with real people who might use the product you’re designing.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/9oslXLT.png" alt="Prepare for the interview: Interview preparation checklist as the the user researches on the computer" title="Conducting User Interviews 12"><figcaption>Conducting User Interviews 17</figcaption></figure>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re conducting interviews in person or online, it’s important to be prepared before you speak with real users. You want to make the most of your limited time together and learn as much as you can about their unique perspectives. Here are a few things you can do to prepare for interviews:</p>



<span id="more-18929"></span>



<p><strong>Script interview questions. </strong>Develop a list of questions that you’ll ask all of the users you interview. It&#8217;s considered a best practice to keep interview questions fairly consistent across users, but this list of questions is just a guide. You can deviate from the questions you prepared, if necessary, to learn more about the user and their pain points.</p>



<p><strong>Collect supplies.</strong> Create a checklist of items you&#8217;ll need for the interview, such as a computer, a printed list of questions, or paper and a pencil. If you&#8217;re using new equipment or technology during the interview, make sure you know how it works in advance.</p>



<p><strong>Research the users.</strong> Take time to learn what you can about the people you’ll interview. If the users you’re preparing to interview provide their personal information before the interview, be sure to take note of it. This information might include their name, demographic information, relevant experience with the product you’re designing, or details about how they learned about the interview. You can use this information to extend the conversation during the interview and build a rapport. When you work for an organization, you can also screen participants on sites like LinkedIn to confirm they are who they say they are. You wouldn’t want to accidentally interview someone who is working for the competition!</p>



<p><strong>Practice.</strong> It’s always a good idea to practice delivering the questions you’ll ask users before you conduct a real interview. This gives you time to make changes to the questions you’re planning to ask and helps ensure that the interviews run smoothly. Practicing is also a good way to determine if the length of the interview is appropriate, or if you need to add or cut questions from your list. You can practice asking interview questions in front of a mirror or with a trusted colleague.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/KILMXTn.png" alt="Meet the partcipant. The user and researcher shake hands as the researcher says, &quot;How has your day been?&quot;" title="Conducting User Interviews 13"><figcaption>Conducting User Interviews 18</figcaption></figure>



<p>First impressions matter! As you meet users for the first time, at the start of an interview, you want the conversation to be set up for success. Here are a few things you can do when meeting interview participants:</p>



<p><strong>Build a rapport. </strong>Building a good rapport is all about establishing a professional, but friendly, interaction. Making light conversation, like asking how the user&#8217;s day has been, can help establish a relationship before the interview begins. Simple questions and welcoming gestures can put the user at ease, which will help them share their true feelings once the interview begins.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Thank users for coming.</strong> Before the interview begins, show gratitude to the people you’re interviewing for taking the time to meet with you and share their perspectives. Thanking users is a part of establishing a good rapport and can help them feel like their opinions are valued.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Gather basic details.</strong> As you meet users, remember to ask about basic information that&#8217;s relevant to the interview, such as their name or demographic details.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/vdPlkj3.png" alt="Conduct the interview: The researcher is asking the interviewee questions." title="Conducting User Interviews 14"><figcaption>Conducting User Interviews 19</figcaption></figure>



<p>Conducting interviews as a way to empathize with users is all about making the user feel comfortable and asking lots of questions. Here are a couple of things to keep in mind as you conduct interviews:</p>



<p><strong>Follow interview etiquette.</strong> Speak in a clear and concise manner while asking questions, and remain professional no matter how users answer a question. Show that you are actively listening while users share their perspectives, such as nodding, making appropriate eye contact, or writing notes.</p>



<p><strong>Ask open-ended questions. </strong>Avoid asking questions that would lead to a simple “yes” or “no” answer. Instead, ask questions that start with “why.” For example, avoid asking &#8220;Do you like going to the library?&#8221; and instead ask &#8220;Why do you like or dislike going to the library?&#8221; This will allow for more detailed conversations and can reveal useful information to include in the product you&#8217;re designing. If the participant does provide a short “yes” or “no” answer, you should ask a follow-up question to get them to share more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/SZ0Zg6m.png" alt="Take Notes. The researcher sits across from the researcher and takes notes." title="Conducting User Interviews 15"><figcaption>Conducting User Interviews 20</figcaption></figure>



<p>Interviews tend to happen quickly. Without taking notes, recounting exactly what participants expressed can be nearly impossible! As you watch and listen to participants during the interview, write down as much as you can capture. A robust list of notes will be helpful when you create empathy maps, and when you come up with ideas to solve users’ pain points. Here are a few best practices to help you take notes during interviews:</p>



<p><strong>Highlight compelling quotes.</strong> The most obvious part of an interview is to take notes on what the user says. Interesting quotes are strong indicators about how users really think and feel. Including quotes in your empathy maps is a great way to feature a firsthand perspective from a real user, which can provide valuable insight when you begin your designs.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Document observations about participants. </strong>It&#8217;s important to record not only what users say, but also their mood, expressions, body language, and behaviors. Pay special attention to outside factors, like a noise or distraction, that might skew interview responses. All of these observations will be important to consider when creating empathy maps.</p>



<p><strong>Consider recording interviews. </strong>Ask participants if they will allow you to record their interview. If they consent, recorded interviews can be really helpful later, for revisiting parts of an interview that you might not remember or taking additional notes after the interview concludes.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/aegS6kV.png" alt="aegS6kV" title="Conducting User Interviews 16"><figcaption>Conducting User Interviews 21</figcaption></figure>



<p>After you&#8217;ve asked all of the interview questions, give users a chance to share their final thoughts about any items discussed during the interview. Some participants might open up about their opinions and reveal insights that they didn’t share earlier.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, remember to thank participants once more. You want participants to leave the interview feeling good about you, your future product, and the brand you might be representing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/07/conducing-user-interviews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Understand empathy in UX design</title>
		<link>/2021/07/understand-empathy-in-ux-design/</link>
					<comments>/2021/07/understand-empathy-in-ux-design/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 09:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[empathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The name UX design says it all: the user’s experience is at the center of how we design products. The best way for you to create great user experiences is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The name UX design says it all: the user’s experience is at the center of how we design products. The best way for you to create great user experiences is to know and empathize with your user. As you might recall, <strong>empathy </strong>is the ability to understand someone else’s feelings or thoughts in a situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a UX designer, empathizing with users enhances the products you create because you experience the product as your user does. The better you are at anticipating a user’s desires and needs, the more comfortable the user will feel with your design, and the more likely they will be to engage with your product long-term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s explore how empathy can make you a more effective UX designer!</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">How to empathize with users</h5>



<p>If empathizing with users sounds like a big task, fear not! The ability to empathize with users is a skill that can be learned with practice. Here are six tips that can help you become a more empathetic UX designer.</p>



<span id="more-18848"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/HkHYY13.png" alt="Icon of question marks, next to heading: Ask lots of questions" title="Understand empathy in UX design 22"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 29</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Ask lots of questions. </strong>As a UX designer, you cannot make assumptions about the needs of your users. Instead, ask your users directly about their needs and wants, which your product design can address. Ask questions that begin with what, how, and why to gain a deeper understanding of your users’ perspective.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/uQ14gnt.png" alt="Icon of a video camera, and a heading that reads &quot;Become more observant&quot;" title="Understand empathy in UX design 23"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 30</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Become more observant</strong>. Shift your focus to the whole user and not just the words they are using. In interviews where the user is physically present or on a video recording, watching a user interact with you or your product can provide physical cues that can affect your research outcomes. To help capture observations, you’ll take detailed notes or even record your sessions with users.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/ffOa3kj.png" alt="Icon of an ear, and a heading that reads &quot;be an active listener&quot;" title="Understand empathy in UX design 24"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 31</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Be an active listener</strong>. Active listening requires you to fully concentrate on, understand, and remember what is being said by the user you’re interacting with. Avoid getting distracted by where the conversation is going or what you might say next. In UX design, practicing active listening can help you get impartial feedback directly from your users, which you can apply to improve your designs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/iqpzRQv.png" alt="Icon of a person with arrows pointing towards them, and a heading that reads &quot;request input&quot;" title="Understand empathy in UX design 25"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 32</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Request input. </strong>It’s important that the feedback you receive is objective and unbiased. Friends or colleagues often provide biased, mostly positive feedback because they want to support or please you. So, it’s important to request input from a variety of sources and a diverse group of users. When asking for feedback, use open-ended questions to understand the user’s actual thoughts on the experience or product.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/IvD1AzK.png" alt="Icon of a silhouette of a head, opening up to reveal a brain, heading that reads &quot;Have an open mind&quot;" title="Understand empathy in UX design 26"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 33</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Have an open mind. </strong>We all have biases. Remember, a <strong>bias</strong> is favoring or having prejudice against something or someone, based on limited information. As UX designers, we have to set those biases aside to better empathize with others. Your goal is to understand users, not to complicate their feedback with your own opinions and emotions.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/fYy6hxK.png" alt="Icon of a magnifying glass, heading that reads &quot;Keep current on UX research&quot;" title="Understand empathy in UX design 27"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 34</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Keep current on UX research</strong>. Follow researchers and join online communities to stay up-to-date on the research that affects UX designers and the users you’re designing for. Research is always changing and evolving as we understand more about human psychology. Staying current will give you an advantage in how you understand and interact with your audience.&nbsp;</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Empathy vs. sympathy&nbsp;</h5>



<p>Empathy is sometimes confused with sympathy, but the two terms don’t mean the same thing. <strong>Empathy</strong> means understanding someone’s feelings or thoughts, often by feeling the emotions yourself. <strong>Sympathy</strong> is the experience of showing concern or compassion without feeling the emotions themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/B5bEvl2.gif" alt="B5bEvl2" title="Understand empathy in UX design 28"><figcaption>Understand empathy in UX design 35</figcaption></figure>



<p>By empathizing effectively with your users and doing your best to understand their needs, you build a great foundation for a product experience that will help solve their unique problems.&nbsp;</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">What does empathy mean to you?</h5>



<p>Designing with empathy will enhance the products you create. By building deeper connections with users, you’ll better understand their perspectives and pain points. Finding that connection early can guide you down the right design path and save you from extensive revisions of your product during a later phase of the design process.</p>



<p>With a focus on empathy, you can design a product that offers users everything they need and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To learn more, check out <a href="https://www.dailymotion.com/video/x28nj7a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>this video on the power of empathy</u></a> from Dr. Brené Brown.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/07/understand-empathy-in-ux-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Common UX Research Methods</title>
		<link>/2021/07/common-ux-research-methods/</link>
					<comments>/2021/07/common-ux-research-methods/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux research types]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Understanding your users is one of the most essential parts of UX design. You’ve already learned about the problems that can come up when designers make assumptions about their users [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Understanding your users is one of the most essential parts of UX design. You’ve already learned about the problems that can come up when designers make assumptions about their users and their needs. So how do you avoid making those assumptions? By doing research! In this reading, you’ll explore some common research methods used by UX designers.</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Types of research</h5>



<p>There are two ways to categorize research: <em>who conducts</em> the research and the <em>type of data</em> collected.</p>



<p>The first way to categorize research is based on whoconducts the research: primary research and secondary research.</p>



<p><strong>Primary research</strong> is research <em>you</em> conduct yourself. Information from direct interactions with users, like interviews, surveys, or usability studies, are considered primary research.</p>



<p><strong>Secondary research</strong> is research that uses information <em>someone else </em>has put together. For example, using information from sources like books, articles, or journals is considered secondary research.</p>



<p>The second way to categorize research is based on the type of data collected: qualitative or quantitative.</p>



<p><strong>Qualitative research</strong> is primarily collected<em> through observations and conversations</em>. Qualitative research is based on understanding users’ needs and aims to answer questions like “why” or “how did this happen?”</p>



<p><strong>Quantitative research</strong> focuses on data that can be <em>gathered by counting or measuring</em>. Quantitative research is based on numerical data that’s often collected from large-scale surveys. This type of research aims to answer questions like “how many?” and “how much?”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/AWPPz96.png" alt="AWPPz96" title="Common UX Research Methods 36"><figcaption>Common UX Research Methods 40</figcaption></figure>



<p>All four of these types of research can intermix. Primary and secondary research can be both qualitative and quantitative. For example, an interview is <em>qualitative </em>research. An interview conducted by you is <em>primary </em>research. If you review an article about an interview conducted by someone else, it’s <em>secondary </em>research. It’s important to be able to identify the difference between these types of research because the data you collect forms the basis of your design decisions.</p>



<span id="more-17912"></span>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Primary research methods</h5>



<p>Now that you understand the different types of research, let’s review some common primary research methods for gathering information.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/apJ3b0y.png" alt="apJ3b0y" title="Common UX Research Methods 37"><figcaption>Common UX Research Methods 41</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Interviews </strong>are a research method used to collect in-depth information on people&#8217;s opinions, thoughts, experiences, and feelings. Interviews can be performed one-on-one or in a group setting, like a focus group.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interviews can take the form of qualitative and quantitative research. A qualitative research method includes open-ended questions that require participants to explain their answers by providing more details.&nbsp;A quantitative research method includes only close-ended questions, like questions that require only “yes”&nbsp; or “no” responses or set multiple choice questions.</p>



<p>Best practice is to conduct at least five user interviews during your research. As you conduct your interviews, you’ll start to find similarities in the feedback that users provide about what works and what doesn’t work about your product. This is exactly the kind of feedback you want!&nbsp;</p>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Advantages</h6>



<ul><li>You’re better able to understand what a user thinks and why.</li><li>You can adjust your questions or refocus the discussion based on the user’s answers.</li><li>You have the ability to ask follow-up questions in real time.</li><li>You have the ability to ask questions specific to a user’s needs.</li><li>You’ll receive direct suggestions from the user.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Disadvantages</h6>



<ul><li>It’s time-consuming to interview each user.&nbsp;</li><li>It’s expensive to pay participants and to rent space for the interviews.</li><li>The sample sizes are smaller, due to time and money constraints.</li><li>Group interviews can be affected by the bandwagon effect, or going along with the group’s opinion instead of thinking creatively, which can discourage open discussion by people who have an opinion that doesn’t align with the majority of the group.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>If you want to learn more about interviews, check out <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/user-interviews/#:~:text=Topics%3A,of%20learning%20about%20that%20topic." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>an article about user interviews</u></a> from the Nielsen Norman Group.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/sUGgdPU.png" alt="sUGgdPU" title="Common UX Research Methods 38"><figcaption>Common UX Research Methods 42</figcaption></figure>



<p>A <strong>survey </strong>is an activity where many people are asked the same questions in order to understand what most people think about a product. Surveys are a great way to measure the success of your product, during development and after it’s launched. For example, sending surveys after a product is released can help you measure the effectiveness of your product and provide a foundation for future improvements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can design surveys to include open-ended questions for qualitative research, which allow research participants to clarify their survey responses, as well as close-ended questions for quantitative research, which generate numerical data.</p>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Advantages</h6>



<ul><li>You can learn more from a larger sample size.</li><li>You are able to gather results and insights quickly.&nbsp;</li><li>Surveys are usually inexpensive because they don’t take as much time for participants to complete, and they can be done remotely.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Disadvantages</h6>



<ul><li>Surveys often do not allow for in-depth feedback; most questions will have responses drawn from a set of multiple-choice answers.&nbsp;</li><li>There are some types of research questions that won’t work in a survey format.</li><li>Surveys usually do not allow for personalization.</li></ul>



<p>If you want to learn more about surveys, check out usability.gov&#8217;s <a href="https://www.usability.gov/how-to-and-tools/methods/online-surveys.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>article about online surveys</u></a>.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/vLjbm1u.png" alt="vLjbm1u" title="Common UX Research Methods 39"><figcaption>Common UX Research Methods 43</figcaption></figure>



<p>A <strong>usability study </strong>is a technique used to evaluate a product by testing it on users. Usability studies help demonstrate if a product is on the right track or if the design needs to be adjusted. There are lots of ways to test usability, both in person and online. It’s a good idea to record your usability sessions, either audio or video, so you can reference the user data as you make design decisions later on in the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Qualitative research is based on observations, and a critical part of conducting usability studies is observing how participants interact with the product you’ve designed. Focusing on qualitative research during usability studies can generate more personal insights by assessing the behavior of users as they experience the product. Quantitative research can also be used when conducting usability studies to understand participants’ impressions of the product.</p>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Advantages</h6>



<ul><li>You can learn from first-hand user interaction and observation.&nbsp;</li><li>Usability studies can challenge your assumptions about your product by demonstrating a completely different result than you were expecting.&nbsp;</li><li>Users can provide in-depth feedback.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Disadvantages</h6>



<ul><li>Usability studies only measures how easy it is to use a product.</li></ul>



<ul><li>This type of research can be expensive, especially if it’s conducted in person.&nbsp;</li><li>There can be differences between a “controlled” usability study in a lab versus how a user experiences the product in their real life.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>If you want to learn more about usability tests, check out the Nielsen Norman Group&#8217;s <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/usability-testing-101/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>article on usability testing</u></a>.</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Secondary research methods</h5>



<p>Secondary researchcan be completed at any phase of the project, since you’re using information from outside sources. In other words, secondary research is not a direct result of your product or the user you’re designing for. The information you discover during secondary research might lay a foundation for your primary research, so you have a better idea of where to focus your efforts. Or, secondary research might supplement the findings from your primary research for a project, to reiterate or strengthen your conclusions.</p>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Advantages</h6>



<ul><li>Secondary research is generally cheaper and faster than primary research. This means you’ll save time and money.&nbsp;</li><li>You can often find secondary research via online searches and subscription research publications.</li><li>Secondary research can be a good supplement to findings from your primary research.</li></ul>



<h6 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Disadvantages</h6>



<ul><li>You will not learn from any first-hand user interaction.</li><li>You will not receive user feedback specific to your product.</li><li>Secondary research can be misleading and generalizing if not done appropriately.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>If you want to learn more about secondary research, check out <a href="https://www.formpl.us/blog/secondary-research" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>an article about secondary research</u></a> from Formplus.</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Research in practice</h5>



<p>As you move forward in your UX design career, you’ll likely get to experience using several different types of research methods. Knowing the advantages and disadvantages of each method, and when to use each, can make your research more effective and can improve your product’s design.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you want to explore research further, check out <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/which-ux-research-methods/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>this user-experience research methods article</u></a> from NN Group. It will guide you through choosing the best research method for you out of 20 popular options.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/07/common-ux-research-methods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce</title>
		<link>/2021/07/different-types-of-ux-researches-in-the-product-development-cylce/</link>
					<comments>/2021/07/different-types-of-ux-researches-in-the-product-development-cylce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product design cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product development life cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are two key parts to every UX design project: conducting research to learn about the users you’re designing for, and gathering feedback about their perspectives. UX design is all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There are two key parts to every UX design project: conducting research to learn about the users you’re designing for, and gathering feedback about their perspectives. UX design is all about putting the user first, and research helps designers understand those users.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>UX research</strong> focuses on understanding user behaviors, needs, and motivations through observation and feedback. Your product design should be built upon research and facts, not assumptions. UX research aligns what you, as the designer, <em>think</em> the user needs with what the user <em>actually</em> needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember the product development life cycle from an earlier course of the program? The <strong><a href="/2021/06/the-product-design-process-or-cycle-to-be-exact/" data-type="post" data-id="15018">product development life cycle</a></strong> has five stages — brainstorm, define, design, test, and launch — that take an idea for an app, website, or product to its launch. </p>



<p>Let’s check out how research fits into the product development life cycle.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/PEEsHKl.png" alt="Graphic showing the product development lifecycle, represented by a circle" title="Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 44"><figcaption>Around the circle, there are other icons that represent the phases of the product development lifecycle &#8211; Brainstorm, Define, Design, Test, Launch. New additional phases branch out from the cycle, including Foundational research (from the brainstorm phase), Design research (from the design phase), and post-launch research (from the launch phase)</figcaption></figure>



<span id="more-17892"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/i1pLuMG.png" alt="icon of a person holding a magnifying glass; text reads: foundational research" title="Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 45"><figcaption>Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 48</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Foundational research</strong> is always done <em>before</em> you start designing. Within the product development life cycle, foundational research happens during the brainstorm stage (stage one) to help you empathize with users, understand their needs, and inspire new design directions. During this stage, you will also make personas and user stories, which you&#8217;ll learn about soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In foundational research, your goal is to figure out what the user needs and how to address those needs with your product. Strong foundational research can contradict your personal perspective on what a good solution might be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Questions you might consider during foundational research include:</p>



<ul><li>What should we build?</li><li>What are the user’s problems?</li><li>How can we solve those problems?</li><li>Am I aware of my own biases, and am I able to filter them as I do research?</li></ul>



<p>There are lots of research methods for conducting foundational research, but many of them are based on observations. Common foundational research methods include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Interviews:</strong> A research method used to collect in-depth information on people&#8217;s opinions, thoughts, experiences, and feelings. You’ll often conduct interviews of your target users themselves.</li><li><strong>Surveys:</strong> An activity where many people are asked the same questions in order to understand what most people think about a product.</li><li><strong>Focus groups:</strong> A small group of people whose reactions are studied. For example, your focus group might bring together eight users to discuss their perspectives about new features in your design. A focus group is usually run by a moderator who guides the group on a certain topic of conversation.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Competitive audit:</strong> An overview of your competitors’ strengths and weaknesses. You&#8217;ll conduct your own competitive audit later in the course, so you will understand this research method well!&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Field studies:</strong> Research activities that take place in the user&#8217;s context or personal environment, rather than in an office or lab.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Diary studies:</strong> A research method used to collect qualitative data about user behaviors, activities, and experiences over time. Often, a user will log, or diary, about their daily activities and provide information about their behaviors and needs, which can help inform your designs.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/wolj3qp.png" alt="icon of a profile of a head with tools and icons coming out of the top; text reads: design research" title="Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 46"><figcaption>Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 49</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Design research</strong> is done <em>while</em> you design. Within the product development lifecycle, design research happens during the design stage (stage three) to help inform your designs, to fit the needs of users, and to reduce risk. Each time you create a new version of your design, new research should be done to evaluate what works well and what needs to be changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In design research, your goal is to answer the question: How should we build it?</p>



<p>The amount of design research you conduct will vary depending on where you work and what you’re building. The most common method used to conduct design research is a <strong>usability study</strong>, which is a technique to evaluate a product by testing it on users. The goal of usability studies is to identify pain points that the user experiences with your prototypes, so the issues can be fixed before the product launches. You’ll conduct your own usability study in the next course of this certificate program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additional research methods that might be used to conduct design research include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>A/B testing</strong>: A research method that evaluates and compares two different aspects of a product to discover which of them is most effective. For example, you might have users evaluate two layouts for the homepage of your app to find out which layout is more effective.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Cafe or guerrilla studies:</strong> A research method where user feedback is gathered by taking a design or prototype into the public domain and asking passersby for their thoughts. For example, you might sit in a local coffee shop and ask customers if they would be willing to test your app design for a couple of minutes and provide feedback.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Card sorting: </strong>A research method that instructs study participants to sort individual labels written on notecards into categories that make sense to them. This type of research is largely used to figure out the information architecture of your project, which we’ll discuss in the next course of the program — Course 3: Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Designs.</li><li><strong>Intercepts: </strong>A research method that gathers on-site feedback from users as they engage in the activities being researched. Intercepts are often conducted in the field, so this type of research is often considered a subset of field research. An intercept study can provide quick, high-level feedback.</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/7RN3kRr.png" alt="icon of a rocket ship in front of a laptop screen; text reads: post-launch research" title="Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 47"><figcaption>Different types of UX researches in the product development cylce 50</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Post-launch research</strong> is done <em>after</em> the design is complete and your product has launched. Within the product development life cycle, post-launch research happens after the launch stage (stage five) to help validate that the product is meeting user needs through established metrics.</p>



<p>In post-launch research, your goal is to answer the question: Did we succeed? This research will tell you how your final product is performing based on established metrics, such as adoption, usage, user satisfaction, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should use research methods that give insight into what the user thinks of your product and if their experience using your product aligns with how you intended it to function. Research methods you might use to conduct post-launch research include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>A/B testing</strong></li><li><strong>Usability studies</strong></li><li><strong>Surveys</strong></li><li><strong>Logs analysis:</strong> A research method used to evaluate recordings of users while they interact with your design, tools, etc.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">The key to a user-focused product: Research</h5>



<p>Research is crucial to creating a product that satisfies users. As an entry-level designer, it might be tempting to assume what the user needs based on your own experience, but as you know: The user comes first. Always make sure that your opinions are backed up by your research. You should get feedback from your users before, during, and after you design!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/07/different-types-of-ux-researches-in-the-product-development-cylce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Overcoming impostor syndrome</title>
		<link>/2021/07/overcoming-impostor-syndrome/</link>
					<comments>/2021/07/overcoming-impostor-syndrome/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imposter syndrome]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever felt like you aren’t quite good enough, even though you actually are? Feeling like you aren’t good enough to do a certain job or mingle with certain [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Have you ever felt like you aren’t quite good enough, even though you actually are? Feeling like you aren’t good enough to do a certain job or mingle with certain people happens to more people than you might think. In fact, feeling this way is so common that it even has a name: impostor syndrome.</p>



<p><strong>Impostor syndrome</strong> is the belief that you’re unskilled, inferior to others, or bad at your job, despite your successes. We’ve all felt impostor syndrome at some point in our lives. If you’re feeling impostor syndrome, you’re certainly not alone!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/YhebYBq.png" alt="YhebYBq" title="Overcoming impostor syndrome 51"><figcaption>Overcoming impostor syndrome 53</figcaption></figure>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Effects of impostor syndrome</h5>



<p>Impostor syndrome can cause anxiety and low confidence that can stop you from becoming the most successful version of yourself. Impostor syndrome can manifest in many ways, and each person’s experience is unique. You might have seen or personally experienced impostor syndrome in situations like:&nbsp;</p>



<span id="more-16742"></span>



<ul><li>Not applying to jobs unless you meet every requirement (even though you totally don’t have to!).</li><li>Taking on extra work to make sure you’re “doing it all” and to look more capable in front of your peers.</li><li>Not attending networking events or career fairs because you’re nervous or anxious.</li><li>Downplaying your abilities during conversations.</li><li>Shrugging off compliments because you don’t believe them.</li></ul>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Manage impostor syndrome</h5>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/ySPqdCv.png" alt="ySPqdCv" title="Overcoming impostor syndrome 52"><figcaption>Overcoming impostor syndrome 54</figcaption></figure>



<p>We want you to meet new people with confidence and without letting impostor syndrome get in the way. Here are a few pro tips to manage those anxious feelings:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Acknowledge your thoughts.</strong> Recognize how you’re feeling, and try to pinpoint why you’re feeling that way. This will help you figure out what triggers your impostor syndrome, so that you can better manage it in the future.</li><li><strong>Own your accomplishments. </strong>You have your own unique perspectives and experiences. Think of all of the accomplishments and skills that make you different from the next person. Write them down in a list so that you can see just how much you have to talk about when you network. You have plenty to offer, so go into conversations with confidence!</li><li><strong>Be honest with yourself. </strong>Do a realistic evaluation of your strengths and weaknesses. Finding areas that create the feeling of not “being good enough” and working to improve them will help you feel more confident in yourself. <em>Everyone</em> has areas where they can improve, and there’s always more to learn, so don’t let your weaknesses hold you back.</li><li><strong>Have a conversation.</strong> Ask a trusted mentor, friend, or seasoned professional how they handle impostor syndrome.</li><li><strong>Wear something that makes you feel confident.</strong> Looking good helps you feel good. If you’re going to an in-person networking event, put on your favorite professional attire so that you feel like the best version of yourself.</li><li><strong>Help someone else. </strong>Sharing the knowledge that you have with others helps you feel more valuable. This could be giving advice to someone less experienced than you or sharing a unique experience with one of your peers. If you think you don’t have anything to offer anyone else, refer back to the list you made earlier.</li><li><strong>Fake it till you make it. </strong>Even if you don’t feel confident in your abilities as a designer, if you <em>act </em>confident for long enough, eventually it will become second nature to you. People are naturally drawn to confident individuals, so acting confidently will likely help you make even more connections within your workplace and the UX community.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Go with a friend.</strong> Attending networking events with someone you know can help you feel less overwhelmed and nervous.</li><li><strong>Get to know people.</strong> Becoming more familiar with other UX professionals will make you feel less out of place. You’ll come to realize that experienced UX designers aren’t as intimidating as they may initially seem! This will help you feel less nervous in the future when you meet other people.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Know that you&#8217;re not alone.</strong> If you’re going to a networking event, or you’re starting a group project with people you don’t know, you won’t be the only one who feels they don’t belong. Being around experienced professionals can be intimidating, even if you’re one yourself! Plus, even the most experienced UX designers were once in your shoes. We all started somewhere.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Networking and growing your career is all about learning, <em>not</em> about being perfect. Don’t hold yourself to unreasonable standards. Instead, work to be the best designer you can be, be confident in who you are, and keep growing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/07/overcoming-impostor-syndrome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is a retrospective?</title>
		<link>/2021/06/what-is-a-retrospective/</link>
					<comments>/2021/06/what-is-a-retrospective/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 09:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retro questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retrospective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sprint]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you operate in an Agile/Scrum work pipeline, at the end of each sprint you&#8217;ll be asked to participate in a &#8216;retrospective&#8217; meeting (or &#8216;retro&#8217;, for short). A retrospective is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you operate in an Agile/Scrum work pipeline, at the end of each sprint you&#8217;ll be asked to participate in a &#8216;retrospective&#8217; meeting (or &#8216;retro&#8217;, for short). </p>



<p>A <strong>retrospective</strong> is a collaborative critique of the design sprint. The goal of a retrospective is to make sure everyone who took part in the sprint has the chance to give feedback and think about opportunities for improvement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The key questions to ask during a retrospective are:&nbsp;</p>



<ol><li>What went well?&nbsp;</li><li>What can be improved?&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>Answering these questions will help you work better as a team and as an individual. Make sure everyone feels empowered to share their experiences, and that personal identifiers, like race or gender, don’t prevent members from being honest. Before the retrospective begins, tell the group that any feedback provided will be used to reflect on the experience and improve the process for the next sprint.&nbsp;</p>



<span id="more-16188"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/huLUCs7.png" alt="A graphic of a shining trophy with the text &quot;what went well?&quot; written underneath" title="What is a retrospective? 55"><figcaption>What is a retrospective? 58</figcaption></figure>



<p>Start the retrospective by discussing the parts of the design sprint that were successful and areas where the team did well. Maybe a new process was created that could be applied to future sprints. Or maybe the addition of a new digital tool enhanced the team’s productivity. Analyze your team’s wins, and think about how they could be applied to future sprints.</p>



<p>Questions you might ask during this part of the retrospective include:</p>



<ul><li>Which tools saved you the most time and effort?</li><li>When did you feel the most satisfaction?</li><li>What helped you make your best contribution to the team during this sprint?</li></ul>



<p>This is also a good time to acknowledge a team member’s strong performance. Celebrating successes builds relationships and increases cohesion and harmony within the team!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/fBxL8qQ.png" alt="" title="What is a retrospective? 56"><figcaption>What is a retrospective? 59</figcaption></figure>



<p>After highlighting everything that went well, it’s time to shift gears and think about areas for improvement. Your team will want to know what went wrong, so that you all can do better next time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Encourage everyone to participate in sharing areas for improvement. You might even take turns going around a circle and adding challenges to a shared list. If anyone is nervous about speaking up, invite each person to write their thoughts anonymously on individual sticky notes. Then, all of the improvements can be reviewed together. This eliminates concerns about causing offense and reduces the chance of groupthink. <strong>Groupthink </strong>can occur in a group discussion when one person shares an opinion and everyone immediately agrees with the opinion, instead of sharing their own feelings about a topic. Groupthink prevents each person from having an equal say, and it might mean certain areas for improvement are overlooked.</p>



<p>Consider each phase of the design sprint to structure the feedback: understand, ideate, decide, prototype, and test. At what point were there missteps? What caused those challenges? Share your perspective if a phase or two didn’t go according to plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Questions you might ask during this part of the retrospective include:</p>



<ul><li>What went wrong that caught you off guard?</li><li>Which problems came up the most often?</li><li>When do you think we experienced the biggest challenge as a team?</li></ul>



<p>Then, examine the sprint’s outcome or final product, and ask questions like:</p>



<ul><li>Did the team overestimate or underestimate the work required to complete the design?</li><li>Did an external factor derail your productivity?</li><li>And most importantly, does the final design actually solve the user problem?</li></ul>



<p>Identify ways that the team could have ended up with a better solution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Keep in mind, retrospectives are about empowering, not shaming. This is not the time to call out an individual for poor performance. If you have issues with a team member’s work, it’s best to address it with that person privately, not during a team-wide retrospective.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/9a98S4Y.png" alt="An icon of a file, a piece of paper and a pencil. Text underneath reads &quot;lessons learned&quot;" title="What is a retrospective? 57"><figcaption>What is a retrospective? 60</figcaption></figure>



<p>By the end of the retrospective meeting, your team will have a better understanding of what went well and what could be improved. Naturally, you’ll want to take lessons learned into your next design sprint.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before your next sprint, review the conclusions you reached at the end of the last retrospective. Your conclusions should inform how you conduct the next sprint. Perhaps you need to include a more diverse team, allow more time for ideating, or test with additional users before moving forward with a design.</p>



<p>Questions you might ask include:</p>



<ul><li>What did you discover during the sprint that you’re still wondering about?</li><li>How could the current process be holding the team back from creating better solutions?</li></ul>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Takeaways</h5>



<p>Remember: Speak up and share your suggestions for how the next design sprint could be better. Don’t be afraid to suggest anything you think will improve the project or next sprint. The only bad suggestion is the one not shared!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/06/what-is-a-retrospective/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle</title>
		<link>/2021/06/designing-for-multiple-platforms-the-four-cs-principle/</link>
					<comments>/2021/06/designing-for-multiple-platforms-the-four-cs-principle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 14:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4cs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design for multiple platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four cs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiplatform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Successfully designing across platforms means providing users with a good experience, no matter what platform they use! As a UX designer, your job is to make sure that your designs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Successfully designing across platforms means providing users with a good experience, no matter what platform they use! As a UX designer, your job is to make sure that your designs account for and take full advantage of the unique features of each platform. When preparing to design across platforms, it’s helpful to keep in mind the four Cs: consistency, continuity, context, and complementary. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/K7Mm2uf.png" alt="Graphic from the point of view of someone looking at their hands on a laptop. They are holding a phone and wearing a watch." title="Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 61"><figcaption>Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 65</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Consistency</strong>: Most companies have specific design guidelines that need to be followed in order to stay consistent with their brand identity, which refers to the visual appearance and voice of a company. When designing a product, it’s essential to stay true to the company’s brand guidelines in order to maintain consistency across platforms and drive brand awareness. Maintaining a consistent design helps improve the user experience and build trust, because users can expect the design to feel familiar across platforms and products.</p>



<span id="more-15666"></span>



<p>Take Google, for example. No matter which Google product or platform you use, you’ll find the colors red, blue, yellow, and green incorporated throughout the design. These visual design details are an essential part of building consistency, trust, and user loyalty.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/anDZpkx.png" alt="A graphic of a laptop and a phone next to each other. On the laptop, there&#039;s an email draft. Same draft is on the phone." title="Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 62"><figcaption>Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 66</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Continuity</strong>: To provide users with a seamless experience as they move between platforms, UX designers also have to prioritize continuity. Continuity in design means that users can maintain their progress as they move from one platform to the next. The user experience for each platform might be slightly different, but the product’s functionality should still be connected. Without continuity, users can become frustrated if the progress of their experience does not carry across platforms.</p>



<p>For example, imagine you’re designing a website and app for emails. A user should be able to start writing an email on their laptop, save it as a draft, and finish that email later on their mobile phone.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/SVmWy8S.png" alt="A graphic of a laptop screen next to a smart watch screen. Email appears on laptop, notification appears on the watch." title="Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 63"><figcaption>Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 67</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Context</strong>: It’s also important to consider the context of each platform you’re designing for. This means thinking about when and how users prefer to interact with certain features on different platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, imagine that a user has an email app on both their laptop and smartwatch. They’re probably not going to compose an entire email on their small smartwatch screen, but they might still want to get notifications about new emails or read important messages. Designers have to take into account the context of the user’s situation and adapt the design for each platform accordingly.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/gZPHxAm.png" alt="A graphic of a laptop next to a phone screen. On the laptop, hands are typing an email. On the phone, they are adding images" title="Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 64"><figcaption>Designing for Multiple Platforms: The Four Cs Principle 68</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Complementary</strong>: One way to create a great cross-platform user experience is to make sure that the design of each platform adds something new for the user.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, imagine you have a family member who lives abroad that you keep in touch with over email. You might write most of your emails to them through the desktop version of the product, but you might build on those emails using the product’s mobile app, which has features like adding photos directly from your phone. Taking into account how each platform could uniquely enrich the overall user experience is the best way to create complementary UX designs.</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Examples of cross-platform experiences</h5>



<p>Now that you have the hang of designing across platforms, check out some real-world examples of products with stellar cross-platform user experiences.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">YouTube&nbsp;</h5>



<p>For a lot of people, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>YouTube</u></a> is a go-to source for watching endless hours of video content. The YouTube mobile viewing experience complements and smoothly transitions from a desktop browser. For example, the mobile app elevates YouTube’s “‘Watch History” feature, which allows users to continue watching from the place they left off in videos, on any device. In the mobile phone app, users can also access all of their playlists and upload videos directly to their channel, just like they would on a computer.&nbsp;</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">WebMD</h5>



<p><a href="https://www.webmd.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>WebMD</u></a> is a healthcare website where users can learn about the symptoms, diagnosis, and treatments related to a wide variety of medical conditions. The WebMD “Symptom Checker” allows users to click on certain areas of a body map and get a list of possible symptoms associated with those body parts. For example, a user can indicate that they’re experiencing heartburn as a symptom by clicking on the chest of the virtual body, and selecting “heartburn” from the provided list. On a mobile phone, this feature is simplified to account for the smaller screen size, but still provides the same basic functionality. On a desktop or laptop computer, this feature is more in-depth and extensive, and lays out the content differently.&nbsp;</p>



<h5 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Airbnb</h5>



<p><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>Airbnb</u></a> is an online rental platform where users can list their own space to rent or book a stay in someone else’s space. Think of Airbnb like a hotel, but you stay in actual homes, instead of a commercial building. The Airbnb user experience on a desktop computer is straightforward and similar to other rental sites, where you can filter your search based on your needs. The mobile app seamlessly integrates these same features and allows for continuity throughout the booking process. You can even get Airbnb notifications on your smartwatch, which is really handy as you’re traveling to your destination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/06/designing-for-multiple-platforms-the-four-cs-principle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My UX Design Toolbox</title>
		<link>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/</link>
					<comments>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 09:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UX Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe after effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe xd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design Toolbelts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UX Design Tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just like carpenters rely on different tools for different tasks, so do UX designers. Start adding some tools to your digital toolbox and explore a few of the most popular [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just like carpenters rely on different tools for different tasks, so do UX designers. Start adding some tools to your digital toolbox and explore a few of the most popular programs that you might use as an entry-level UX designer.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/9RMZiVf.png" alt="A person with long hair stands in front of toolbox holding a laptop. Text above reads wireframing and prototyping tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 69"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 73</figcaption></figure>



<p>Early in your UX design career, you’ll likely spend a lot of time creating wireframes and prototypes.</p>



<ul><li>A <strong>wireframe</strong> is an outline or a sketch of a product or a screen. Wireframes help designers figure out how a page is arranged, where each piece of a product fits in with the others, and how users will likely interact with the product.</li><li>A <strong>prototype</strong> is an early model of a product that demonstrates functionality.</li></ul>



<p>You’ll learn much more about wireframes and prototypes, and create your own, as you progress through this certificate program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are tons of digital tools available to help you design wireframes and prototypes. The most popular tools among them are Figma and Adobe XD due to their availability:</p>



<span id="more-15627"></span>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.figma.com/design/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Figma</u></strong></a> is a widely used, all-in-one wireframing and prototyping tool that allows for real-time collaboration among multiple team members. This makes Figma ideal for designers working remotely and for teams with members in different locations. Figma is versatile and customizable, with plenty of features to speed up the design process. The greatest thing about Figma is its availability. Being a web app, Figma is capable of running on pretty much every computer in existence, regardless of its operating systems (even Linuxes), as long as it is capable of running a modern browser.</li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/xd.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Adobe XD</u></strong></a> is great for editing graphics, building prototypes, and collaborating with other people on your team. It has particularly robust features for tasks that happen during the later stages of UX design, as you get into what we call high-fidelity designs. Unlike Figma which was built on web technologies, Adobe XD is still a traditional desktop application which mean you will need to be running the latest version of either OS X or Windows to be able to use it.</li><li><a href="https://www.sketch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Sketch</u></strong></a> was formerly an extremely popular wireframing and prototyping tool in the UX community. However Sketch can only run on Mac OS X, which means most UX designers will not be able to use it even if they want to (although they recently added a web version to alleviate that somewhat). This couples with the fact that Sketch does not have a free version like Figma or Adobe XD has caused Sketch&#8217;s popularity to crumble in recent years. This was a situation similarly faced by <a href="https://www.framer.com/why-framer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Framer</u></strong></a>, arguably one of the most advanced UX design tools. Framer used to be a paid-only Mac application just like Sketch, but their development team quickly realized such high barrier to entry will severely limit their user base and eventually fade from existence like Sketch. Today Framer is available on both Mac (even the new M1 variant) and Windows, with a free tier similar to Figma.</li></ul>



<p>And of course, there are other tools like UXPin, InVision, MarvelApp that you can discover on your own</p>



<p>Keep in mind that the UX design industry changes often, and so do design tools. Many of the skills we’ll explore as part of this program are transferable, meaning once you know the basics in one tool, like Figma or Adobe XD, that knowledge will transfer to other design tools that look and feel quite similar.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/pUcKZM7.png" alt="A person holding a megaphone stands in front of a toolbox. Text above reads &quot;presentation tools&quot;" title="My UX Design Toolbox 70"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 74</figcaption></figure>



<p>During the early, conceptual phases of the design process, you don’t always need to use tools that were specifically made for UX design. In fact, some designers prefer working within the relative simplicity of presentation programs, especially when they’re creating wireframes. Most presentation tools also have live collaboration features, so team members can interact with each other and collaborate on the designs. Here are three of the most popular presentation tools from Google, Microsoft, and Apple:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://slides.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Slides.com</strong></a> (or <strong><a href="https://slid.es/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://slid.es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">slid.es</a></strong>) is my top choice. It&#8217;s dead simple. It&#8217;s available everywhere. Use it.</li><li><a href="https://workspace.google.com/products/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Google Slides</u></strong></a> is a web-based presentation program included in Google Workspace, Google’s suite of productivity software. Google Slides is free, and anyone with a Google account can create or edit Slides presentations.</li><li><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/powerpoint" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Microsoft PowerPoint</u></strong></a> was one of the first presentation programs created, and it’s still very widely used. PowerPoint is part of the Microsoft 365 program package and comes in both offline and online versions. Although anyone can view a PowerPoint presentation online, you have to own the product to create or edit a presentation.</li><li><a href="https://www.apple.com/keynote/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Keynote</u></strong></a> is Apple’s presentation program, and a lot of people consider its templates to be the most visually appealing. It’s also available both online and offline. Although Keynote was created for Apple devices like Macs and iPads, it can be used on a PC, as well. Similar to PowerPoint, you have to own the product to make edits or create new presentations in Keynote.</li></ul>



<p>In many instances, presentation tools are a matter of preference. Feel free to try out many of them, and pick whichever you feel most comfortable working with!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/flUQ67q.png" alt="A person holding a camera and scissors and standing in front of a toolbox. Text above: image creation and manipulation tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 71"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 75</figcaption></figure>



<p>As you develop your designs, you might need to use tools to create, manipulate, and integrate images and illustrations. Here are two of the most popular image creation and manipulation tools:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/illustrator.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Affinity Designer</u></strong></a> is primarily used for drawing vector images. <strong>Vector images </strong>(or SVGs) are images created using points, curves, lines, and shapes to produce perfectly smooth lines. This makes it easy to edit and resize images in Illustrator. As an entry-level UX designer, you can use Adobe Illustrator to draw prototypes and illustrations for your designs.</li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Affinity Photo</u></strong></a> works primarily with photos, known as raster images. These images are composed of thousands, or even millions, of pixels, the smallest unit of display on a computer screen. While its cousin Illustrator is a better tool for creating an image from scratch, Photoshop has more uses, including image manipulation across file types, saving images for digital publishing, and even presentations.</li></ul>



<p>Now you might be confused with those familiar names. Normally you&#8217;d expect to see Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop filling those slots, and for good reasons. They are decidedly better tools. However Adobe&#8217;s decision to put them in a subscription model had effectively killed them for the smaller independent designers like myself. I&#8217;m not sponsored by them or anything, it&#8217;s just that compare to Adobe, I like Affinity&#8217;s perpetual pricing model MUCH better.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also Gravit Design which was a great project back in the day. It works with both vector and raster images, and it runs on the web! Just like Figma, it can be configured to be used as a desktop application with Electron. Unfortunately it was bought out by Corel, which means it will eventually meet the same fate as Ulead PhotoImpact or JASC Paint Shop Pro. It was a shame really, seeing how it could&#8217;ve overtaken GIMP and Krita as the de facto image editor on Linux.</p>



<p>In all honesty though, most basic image manipulation can already be done in your screen design tool. Figma can handle both SVG Vector and raster images just fine. It can cut, crop, resize, even do basic color correction there. Only use AI and PS if you want to create something more hardcore, because let&#8217;s face it, they are massive resource hogs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/OOjd7BE.png" alt="A person holding a slate while standing in front of a toolbox. Text above reads: animation tools" title="My UX Design Toolbox 72"><figcaption>My UX Design Toolbox 76</figcaption></figure>



<p>Creating animations can be a great way to showcase the more interactive elements of your designs. For example, you could create a Graphics Interchange Format (GIF) to demonstrate how a user might interact with the homepage of an app you’re designing. There are many programs that UX designers can use to create animations, but here are a couple to highlight:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://lottiefiles.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Lottie</u></strong></a> is a tool that helps you edit and ship your animations in just a few clicks. Animation files formatted in Lottie, also known as LottieFiles, use less file space on your hard drive since they are code-based. On Lottie, you can also explore animations created by other designers for inspiration or use. </li><li><a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/aftereffects.html?sdid=KKQOW&amp;mv=search&amp;kw=test&amp;ef_id=Cj0KCQjwuL_8BRCXARIsAGiC51CSU9gu_SrVG40X-2ClEFnFfKuEKYYQ4kOtlm6F3Y4Kon1hf5z6oSwaAvXLEALw_wcB:G:s&amp;s_kwcid=AL!3085!3!469900475182!e!!g!!adobe%20after%20effects&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwuL_8BRCXARIsAGiC51CSU9gu_SrVG40X-2ClEFnFfKuEKYYQ4kOtlm6F3Y4Kon1hf5z6oSwaAvXLEALw_wcB" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><u>Adobe After Effects</u></strong></a> is often used to add motion graphics and visual effects to designs. For example, UX designers might utilize Adobe After Effects to make text move across the screen or create transitions between pages.</li><li><strong><a href="https://rive.app/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rive.app/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rive.app</a></strong> is a spanking new entry into the market. It is used to create smooth animations. Especially popular among those who&#8217;s looking into developing Flutter applications</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/06/my-ux-design-toolbox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
