<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Rants &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/rants/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 01:13:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Rants &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A decade of employment: A personal reflection</title>
		<link>/2022/01/a-decade-of-employment-a-personal-reflection/</link>
					<comments>/2022/01/a-decade-of-employment-a-personal-reflection/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So 2021 was over, a year I believe most of us couldn&#8217;t wait to forget. So much time staying under lockdown, so many losses. I can no longer count with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>So 2021 was over, a year I believe most of us couldn&#8217;t wait to forget. So much time staying under lockdown, so many losses. I can no longer count with my fingers the number of my friends on FB who&#8217;s using a black avatar (a symbol of grievances where I come from).</p>



<p>But, sad pandemic stories aside, this year also marks the 10 year anniversary of me working professionally in the graphic design field, and I guess it&#8217;s a good time as any to take a look back and see how things have changed, and reminisce about people whom I&#8217;ve met along the way, how they helped shaping the man I am today. I will not be censoring company names, as they are publicly available in my resume, as well as my LinkedIn.</p>



<span id="more-21648"></span>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2011-2013: the FiM era</h2>



<p>So the first company I ever work for (officially), was kind of a bust. Pay was low, the daily commute was long, work was unrewarding. They were liquidated very shortly after I quit, and eventually ghosted me of my insurance benefit, I suspect they committed fraud and didn&#8217;t pay the employee insurance they were legally required to, despite deducting it from our salaries every month. I eventually had to have the next company redo my whole insurance book for me because of that. None of that actually surprised me though, having seen the head honcho guy, some real shady mofo who resided in Hong Kong, masquerading as a venture capitalist.</p>



<p>Point is, from a work perspective, it was kinda shit.</p>



<p>But from a personal perspective though, there was&#8230;quite a lot to remember. I owe a lot to my former boss, Ms. O.  Before FiM, I was unemployed for over half a year, struggling to find my place in the world. When I came back from the States, I deeply regretted the decision to spend the previous 3 years in the States, achieving almost nothing. You know what I did during those years in the States? Half of it was spent indoors playing Counter-Strike: Source with my best friend, some of it was spent busing tables at Thai Son Noodles, serving along side people who couldn&#8217;t even read (that&#8217;s a true story I&#8217;d like to tell some other time), and flipping electronics on eBay, Craigslist and fucking Amazon. </p>



<p>During that time, my peers had moved on to work in banks and financial institutions (which is the natural career path for people with degrees like me), even though who chose a different path had at least attempted something else, something they could put down as real work experience. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, I had nothing in my CV despite having left college for over 3 years, who would take me then? </p>



<p>Ms. O took me in and offered me a place as the in house graphic designer, without even so much as asking for a CV. She heard about me from my sister, having initially tried to recruit her. And for that, I am grateful. I don&#8217;t know if she was ever involved with KS&#8217;s (the big boss) shady business practice that eventually led to everyone losing their insurance books or not, I think she might at least have some idea, given that she was the second in command, but even if she was, I&#8217;d never resent her.</p>



<p>Having said that though, I wouldn&#8217;t work for or with her again, not because of what happened with FiM, but because of her skills as a leader/mentor, or more precisely, the lack of it. I can tell she was really passionate about the business, and cared a great deal about building a strong team to back it up. Problem was, she didn&#8217;t possess the talent to do so. It wasn&#8217;t until I left FiM and met some really inspiring leader that I realized I didn&#8217;t learn anything during the 1 year and a half that I was there. At least nothing useful to my profession anyway.</p>



<p>On the personal front however, I made some major milestones during this time period. I got intimate for the first time with a girl from the office (also found out that sleeping nude with another person for a whole night wasn&#8217;t as comfortable as what the movies had led us to believe). We never made it all the way though, because we were never each other&#8217;s type anyway, it was loneliness and most likely pheromones that draw us together. But thanks to her I became a lot more emotionally mature, something that helped me greatly in later days when I meet the girl whom I would eventually marry. She also worked, albeit very briefly, at FiM. Like 2 weeks or something, but that was enough time for us to click. She was married at the time but unhappily, and I patiently waited. We&#8217;re still together now, and I can&#8217;t imagine being with anybody but her, I believe it was the most correct choice I&#8217;ve made in my life.</p>



<p>Toward the end of this era, FiM was stagnating. My job wasn&#8217;t largely unchanged for the last year and a half. Being the only &#8216;graphic design&#8217; guy in the company, I was tasked with literally everything related to graphic. From website design, logo design for potential clients (sometime provided free of charge as an addon to attract customers), to beautifying presentation decks to account managers, to designing company catalogue. I knew the end was near, but I too, was stagnating in looking for a new job. After all, I didn&#8217;t have any experience in that front, FiM was my first job, and the experience I gathered there wasn&#8217;t enough to fill a resume page. I was afraid, but eventually pulled the trigger anyway, after many of the old people left.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2014-2018: the Punch Era (DeNA + EVA)</h2>



<p>This transition was memorable for me, mainly because there was so many &#8216;first&#8217; involved.</p>



<ul><li>First time switching job.</li><li>First time experience with a headhunting agency (Harvey Nash, which as fate would have it, would become my next employer).</li><li>First career path adjustment (from general graphic design to Game UI Design)</li><li>First time having a real team (by that I mean people who also works in graphic design</li><li>First time working in an A-class office building (IPH)</li><li>First time having a foreigner as my direct supervisor (I always wanted a job where my English would be of use)</li><li>First time being sent to another country on a professional capacity (it was only Singapore, which was like a stone throw away, but still)</li></ul>



<p>I was initially interested in Punch because its wiki entry said it was an American company. It wasn&#8217;t until I joined the company that I realized it was bought by DeNA, a rather large Japanese corporation (it was one of the better ones too, as I later found out after Punch got sold yet again).</p>



<p>I had the time of my life at Punch, there was no work-life balance. For the first 2 years or so, work was life, and life was work. The company would provide each employee with around $5 for dinner if they choose to stay at the company after 7pm. &#8216;$5 for dinner&#8217; may not sound like much (redditards antiworkers would probably lose their mind at the sight of that), but it was actually quite sufficient for an average takeaway meal in Vietnam back in &#8217;14. Considering how most of the young employees actually spend less than $3 for their dinners, coupled with the fact that the company didn&#8217;t specify that you have to do company works when they stay the evening, they were pretty much feeding a third of their work force and provide them with an opportunity to have LAN party, doing personal works or just generally horsing around with their friends while all the electricity and AC is paid for.</p>



<p>It was a great time indeed.</p>



<p>It was also during my stay there that I actually know what it&#8217;s like to go on a real business trip abroad. DeNA has this policy to send random people that they deem potential to their office in Singapore for&#8230;uh to be honest I still don&#8217;t know what for. But they&#8217;d routinely send people to Singapore for a 3 to 8 weeks period. I was only on my 4th day at Punch when they slapped an airplane ticket on the table and said that I&#8217;d be leaving next Monday. It was a culture shock indeed but I ain&#8217;t complaining, it was like a free traveling opportunity with all expenses paid for.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not like the days we spent in Singapore was a leisure trip anyway. We were cramped into these super tiny hotel suites that you barely have enough space to put your luggage down. Also I found out the reason why Singaporeans were so much more productive than Vietnamese. I&#8217;d usually leave the office</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/01/a-decade-of-employment-a-personal-reflection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Being nice sucks sometimes</title>
		<link>/2021/09/being-nice-sucks-sometimes/</link>
					<comments>/2021/09/being-nice-sucks-sometimes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I made the mistake of joining another UK Project. Today I finished my voluntary withdrawal from the project, and not on a good term. In my [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A few weeks ago I made the mistake of joining another UK Project. Today I finished my voluntary withdrawal from the project, and not on a good term.</p>



<span id="more-21563"></span>



<p>In my withdrawal request letter I pointed out how the client&#8217;s so called Product Analyst continued to impede the progress for the product. Usually, a Product Analyst&#8217;s role is to write requirements and analytics and work with the designer (me) to come up with the best design solution for the product that we can come up with. This PA however, decides to install herself as the sole UI Designer, she maintains her own version of the design. Ok that&#8217;s fine, that shouldn&#8217;t pose a problem, right? We could work together on that.</p>



<p>Nope. If only.</p>



<p>She wanted me to create a completely new version of the site, completely disregard the current design language being implemented (as she said, and I quote, &#8216;the whole thing is ugly&#8217;). But the kicker is this: I cannot use the same approach as she does. I&#8217;m not even talking about design style, design language, I&#8217;m talking about the actual &#8216;approach&#8217; that you can implement on the screen. Like if she&#8217;s using table to display a list of data on a page, then I will have to come up with another way to do it WITHOUT using table, one that has to be inferior in every way. If I insists on using table, she&#8217;d immediately show her existing design and accuse you of stealing her ideas (!?)</p>



<p>To make it simpler to understand why this makes development impossible, imagine you&#8217;re being asked to make new parts for a car, that is running on the freeway. You&#8217;re not allowed to see any of the existing specs, cannot use the same material. If you want to stop the car, you cannot use the brake mechanism, because the owner of the car is already THINKING about using brakes. If you insists that brakes are the best option, you&#8217;re basically stealing the owner&#8217;s idea for his own product.</p>



<p>If that sounds dumb, that&#8217;s because it is. I&#8217;ve never seen such a workflow.</p>



<p>Obviously I didn&#8217;t use that analogy in my letter, I simply cited irreconcilable difference in the way we work. You know, like an old married couple.</p>



<p>I do admit I felt some regret after sending it in, wondering if I was too harsh with my words.</p>



<p>Today I heard from my PM about their comments on this whole incident, turns out I was the nice one. According to them:</p>



<ol><li>I am, in general, severely lacking professionalism, having abruptly declare to leave the project, and not joining their subsequent daily meeting.</li><li>I provided no tangible input after 3 weeks being on their payroll. The works I did provided was simply replications of their Product Analyst&#8217;s work.</li><li>I had, on at least 4 different occasions, canceled review meeting minutes before starting time because my work wasn&#8217;t ready.</li><li>I&#8217;m unable to take constructive criticism, and I have, get this, personally insulted their Product Analyst.</li></ol>



<p>Most if not all of these were blatant slants of what happened, but I just wanted to preface this by saying I understand why they had to spin it all on me. Being an outsourcing company, they&#8217;re technically our employer, so when an argument happens, whoever&#8217;s nicer loses. I&#8217;ve been barred from sending an official response to them to avoid escalation. Understandable, we still need their business. But that doesn&#8217;t mean I won&#8217;t be giving my response here on my personal blog.</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1631785854879" class="rank-math-list-item">
<div class="rank-math-question ">1. Regarding my professionalism </div>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>I will concede that declaring that I&#8217;ve lost interest in the project and is leaving the project in the middle of a call is the most professional thing to do. I was fuming at the time. This is the one thing I regretted doing. But I can&#8217;t be expected to be joining their Daily meeting after I&#8217;ve already handed in my resignation the day before, can I? </p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1631785990024" class="rank-math-list-item">
<div class="rank-math-question ">2. Regarding &#8216;tangible input&#8217; </div>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>OF COURSE there&#8217;s nothing to show BECAUSE that so called PA made sure nothing I made could be used. Remember, according to her, I have to either choose a non-viable option OR infringe on her work (again, an idea that makes no goddamn sense). </p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-1024x527.png" alt="image" title="Being nice sucks sometimes 1">I wasted a massive amount of effort on this project despite the fact that I&#8217;m only billed at 50% of my effort</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1631786058999" class="rank-math-list-item">
<div class="rank-math-question ">3. Regarding cancellations of FOUR meetings at the last minute due to being &#8216;not ready&#8217;</div>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>This is a lie, and an actually elaborate one at that.<br />So as I&#8217;ve only ever canceled 2 meetings during the course of working with this person, one of which was not even due to work, but due to Microsoft Teams service completely being inaccessible in my country (thanks to the massive amount of students in VN using it for online study at the time, it was the opening day of school in VN). I took a screenshot and send it to her HOURS before our meeting with an explanation.<br />The second time, I feel like I&#8217;ve been tricked. She came on early and asked me if I&#8217;d need more time to finish all the interactions on my prototype, and I naively said yes, more time means more comprehensive prototypes. Thinking back I already felt something was off, she was a lot nicer, more friendly when I agreed to move the meeting. And the next day she&#8217;d ask me again if I want to move it, and when I said no she appears to be visibly disappointed. The thought of this being an elaborate plan to rack up evidence to use against me crossed my mind back then, but by then it was already too late. So yes, I&#8217;m guilty of being gullible on this instance, but that doesn&#8217;t change the fact that she made up a number to make it appear more substantial.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1631786929209" class="rank-math-list-item">
<div class="rank-math-question ">4. Regarding personal insult.</div>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>This is it, this is the one that got me. A straight up lie.<br />During our conversations, heated as they were, I&#8217;ve never made a single personal remark against her person, ever. And if you were there you&#8217;d agree that it takes a tremendous amount of self-control to do that. <br />This is a person that times and again accuse me of &#8216;copying her work&#8217;, &#8216;disappointing skills&#8217;, &#8216;a waste of money&#8217;, &#8216;I&#8217;m basically doing your job for you&#8217;. And also several condescending attempts like asking me if I know a particular English word mean, which is pathetically ironic coming from a person who can barely speak English. If I was going to use the same tactic, I&#8217;d probably laugh hysterically every time she says the word &#8216;cross&#8217; (which is written as &#8216;courses&#8217; in all the document).<br />I guess she took it personal when I mentioned that what she&#8217;s doing is not the responsibility of a Product Analyst. She probably thought I was insinuating that she wasn&#8217;t a real Product Analyst. If this offended her, she probably thought so herself.<br />Everybody whoever worked with me knows that I never make personal attacks, ever. And this accusation is something that I absolutely cannot accept. Of all their spins, this is the most serious one, as it damages my personal reputation.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1631788258120" class="rank-math-list-item">
<div class="rank-math-question ">5. Regarding my inability to take Constructive Criticism</div>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>This one is laughable. I&#8217;m not sure which ones of their so called &#8216;criticism&#8217; that they could qualify as &#8216;constructive&#8217;. I don&#8217;t even know if they even qualify as criticism.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<p>The most infuriating part is that after spewing all these craps, they had to audacity to accuse my company of poor screening before sending candidates their ways, and that they will have to be more careful with the interviewing process next time. The galls of these people.</p>



<h4 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Closing words:</h4>



<p>Being nice sucks, but sometimes you have no choice as an employee. Especially employee of an outsourcing company. I wonder if it&#8217;s high time I make my exit. Let&#8217;s give it a few more time and see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/09/being-nice-sucks-sometimes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Choosing a cloud hosting provider: Digital Ocean vs Linode</title>
		<link>/2021/09/choosing-a-cloud-hosting-provider-digital-ocean-vs-linode/</link>
					<comments>/2021/09/choosing-a-cloud-hosting-provider-digital-ocean-vs-linode/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 07:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital ocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linode]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vultr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m gonna make this short: avoid Digital Ocean like the plague. As you know, my whole website used to be hosted on a VM Instance on Google Cloud Platform. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://blog.back4app.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DigitalOcean-vs-Linode-2-1140x515.png" alt="DigitalOcean vs. Linode | Low-code backend to build modern apps" title="Choosing a cloud hosting provider: Digital Ocean vs Linode 2"></figure>



<p>I&#8217;m gonna make this short: avoid Digital Ocean like the plague.</p>



<p>As you know, my whole website used to be hosted on a VM Instance on Google Cloud Platform. However, the cost of GCP was a little much for my usage so I was looking to migrate to another provider. The most obvious names that comes to mind that wasn&#8217;t &#8216;Big Tech&#8217; (AWS, Azure, Alibaba, Google) are the holy trinity: Digital Ocean, Linode and Vultr (which I didn&#8217;t test).</p>



<p>Among those, Digital Ocean is probably the most well known name.</p>



<p>They&#8217;re everywhere. <br>They seem to have the best UI among the cloud provider (and I&#8217;m a sucker for good UIs). <br>They have a pretty extensive knowledgebase that covers pretty everything in tech. <br>They have a huge marketplace, pretty much every self hosted project you see has a &#8216;Deploy on Digital Ocean droplet&#8217; option.</p>



<p>DO sounds like a no-brainer. So I set out to create my account. Being a skeptical, naturally I sign up using a &#8216;trial&#8217; account that offer a $100 credit for 60-day, there&#8217;s plenty of those on Google if you search for it, but don&#8217;t make the same mistake as I did, the 60-day $100 is a goddamn lie. When I added my credit card, I was told there might be a $1 charge for verification that will be refunded in no more than a week. When I added my first droplet, I was immediately charged $6.15, and I&#8217;m pretty sure it&#8217;s never going to be refunded as a few weeks have passed. </p>



<p>This shady practice alone should be enough of a reason for most of you to avoid DO. And if that wasn&#8217;t enough, there&#8217;s also the performance issue.</p>



<p>I created a nano droplet (the $5/m variant). You may ask why I decided to go for the bottom of the barrel choice even though I have $100 in trial credit. In my opinion, a service is only as good as its bottom line, and testing it should give a pretty good overview of the quality of the service being offered. And boy was that the correct decision.</p>



<p>Performance was good on the first day, but it only goes downhill from there. I have a total of 6 WordPress websites with virtually no traffic (only one of them has like 100 visits per DAY). And yet the droplet was slowed to near unresponsive level when I finished migrating my 4th website. SFTP would constantly timeout. If I try to visit 2 of my sites at the same time, the server would return a 504 error. It was unacceptable.</p>



<p>I was ready to give DO the benefit of doubt and blame the <a href="https://tuoitrenews.vn/news/society/20210907/vietnams-internet-speed-crippled-by-cable-break/62983.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disruption of AAE-1 international internet cable line</a> as a factor (even though the droplet I created was provisioned on the Singapore data center, which shouldn&#8217;t have been affected by that incident. </p>



<p>It was then that I decided to make an account on Linode and give it a shot. The sign up process was exactly the same but they didn&#8217;t even charge me a cent for verification. I fired up a $5 linode, going through the same migration process, and lo&#8217; and behold, everything just worked! All 6 websites up and running without a hitch. The hardest part of the migration was, ironically enough, caused by Digital Ocean. As the websites keep timing out when I try to create Duplicator packages. </p>



<p>Normally to save space on the droplet I&#8217;d make Duplicator send the packages to my Google Drive and my OneDrive Business storage, however on the DO droplet, they couldn&#8217;t even communicate with either Google or Microsoft server at all, forcing me to SFTP in and painfully try to download the package manually, bit by bit (thank god WinSCP can do that without poping up a dialog ever 5 minutes). The failure to communicate with Google and Microsoft&#8217;s server is a testament that the connection problem was with Digital Ocean and not with my ISP.</p>



<p>Anyway just wanted to share my experience. Obviously I&#8217;m not endorsing either Linode or Vultr yet since I&#8217;m only on a trial run with them, but one thing is definite: avoid Digital Ocean.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today, folks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/09/choosing-a-cloud-hosting-provider-digital-ocean-vs-linode/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking back at 2020</title>
		<link>/2021/02/looking-back-at-2020/</link>
					<comments>/2021/02/looking-back-at-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I mean, fucking 2020, amirite? It was one hell of year, or hellish, might I say. Almost every living creature on this planet was affected one way or the other. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">I mean, fucking 2020, amirite? It was one hell of year, or hellish, might I say. Almost every living creature on this planet was affected one way or the other. Despite all the crazy shits that happened during the year, it wasn&#8217;t all bad. I&#8217;d like to take a step back and look at things now.</p>



<p>I know, I know, you&#8217;re probably asking &#8220;Dude, it&#8217;s almost March 2021 now, why the hell are you looking back at 2020 now?&#8221;</p>



<p>Ok first of all, according to the Lunar calendar, it&#8217;s only barely 2 weeks over January now, plus prior to it I had a shit ton of work I need to get done. I don&#8217;t even like doing look back posts like this, but something just happened that prompted me.</p>



<span id="more-14891"></span>



<p>I got a 2nd raise in a year.</p>



<p>Yay me, right? But that&#8217;s not what prompted me to write this blog. No, it&#8217;s a negative experience that occurred over half a year ago that just came back to haunt me as my LM mentioned it again during our talk.</p>



<p>I will rant about it in details later but first let&#8217;s take a look at what I actually managed to get done in 2020.</p>



<h3 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Personal Projects (DIY Builds):</h3>



<ul><li>Planned, purchased equipments and manually setup a complete home surveillance system on my own, complete with remote access on mobile devices. All for under $180 (after I was quoted $500 for the same system from a contractor) . This was prompted by my first break-in ever.</li><li>Recycled a tin chocolate box into a completely functional computer (which I&#8217;m in the process of turning into a Xpenology box)</li><li>Finished setting <a href="/2021/02/hosting-my-own-netflix-on-an-ancient-mac-mini-2011/" data-type="post" data-id="14873">my own media streaming server with remote access</a>, learned a lot about networking during the process.</li><li>Built a new computer (Ryzen 5 3600 + 32GB Neo Trident Z RAM + Galaxy 1070 8GB OC) &#8211; with a custom meshed front panel that I created myself.</li><li>Started work on the Bartop Arcade Cabinet project, hoping to have a working prototype before summer.</li></ul>



<h3 class="has-black-color has-text-color wp-block-heading">Professional Projects (UI/UX Designs):</h3>



<ul><li><strong>A comprehensive media planning and management software for marketing professionals for a subsidiary of IPG MediaBrands, a giant in the media industry.</strong> A massive project which includes multi tenancy, regional reporting, online &amp; offline media scheduling and processing system. This project turned me into a morning person after having to wake up at 6 for conference calls with San Francisco. Unfortunately it was cut short by nCoV, but it was still a pretty interesting case study, which I will definitely do a writeup when I have more time (and clearance for showcasing the works, of course).</li><li><strong>A learning management system for my wife&#8217;s edtech startup: VuiHoc</strong>. A super exciting project aimed at K6 students. &#8220;Cute&#8221; &amp; &#8220;Colorful&#8221; was never my style but I managed to help getting the company off the ground, and it is now one of the force to be reckoned with in the industry here in Vietnam (probably No. 1 if you count only the bootstrapping startups)</li><li><strong>A virtual working space for a Japanese corporation, (whose name I am contractually obligated to not reveal until the product goes live).</strong> A super rushed project which I completed within a single week, but for some reason it became my most celebrated project of the year. Probably due to its sheer difficulty. The whole thing was done in a single week, designed, prototyped, and documented, in Japanese! (made possible only with Figma&#8217;s translation plugins, I will do a writeup on designing multilingual interfaces in Figma later if there&#8217;s any interest). With only me and a BrSE to support with translation, we worked around the clock and delivered a super satisfactory end product. The project implemented some very creative gamification approaches that I will document in another post.</li><li><strong>A car rental service iOS app by a startup funded by Jaguar-Range Rover</strong>, whose name I won&#8217;t be mentioning since I&#8217;m about to rant about them in a sec. It wasn&#8217;t a disaster or anything, I&#8217;m just a little unhappy about the way they handle things to avoid responsibilities toward the end. Despite that, I still got to meet and work with some amazing people, especially UX specialist like Ruko Kuga, so it&#8217;s still a win in my book.</li><li><strong>A bio sample management system for The Wellcome Sanger Institute, a non-profit British genomics and genetics research institute</strong>, part of the Darwin Tree of Life programme.</li></ul>



<p>Now, regarding the car rental project. Here&#8217;s an oversimplified version of what happened:</p>



<p>&#8211; &#8220;Hey Nam, pleasure to meet you!&#8221;<br>&#8211; &#8220;Thanks for the quick turnover Nam, you&#8217;re fast!&#8221;<br>&#8211; &#8220;Wow! These looks great Nam!&#8221;<br>&#8211; &#8220;That&#8217;s fabulous, Nam. Let&#8217;s go with that!&#8221;<br>&#8211; &#8220;Brilliant! Btw, we&#8217;re letting you go today, we already got another designer. Thanksie!&#8221;</p>



<p>Yep, just like that, saying I was caught off-guard was somewhat an understatement. To be clear, I wasn&#8217;t at all upset that it happened, and more or less saw it coming. Their CTO had been hinting about pressure coming down from upstair for weeks. I wasn&#8217;t at all surprised that they&#8217;d replace me with a local designer who understands the local car rental market better AND can jump on a call with them during work hours. No, what pissed me off was that they actually cited poor work quality as the reason for this abrupt change.</p>



<p>Now before you roll your eyes, let me just stop you right there. I know I&#8217;m not the greatest UI Designer in the world, but I do take great pride in my works, and I am very VERY open to constructive criticism, which I received none in this case. The client literally showered me with praises up until the day I was released from the project. If you ever been in a situation where you don&#8217;t know what you did wrong then you&#8217;d know how irritating it is. I strive to better myself every single day, and if there&#8217;s areas I could improve on, I want to know it, no matter how hard it is. So I pushed further for answers.</p>



<p>And guess what?</p>



<p>It wasn&#8217;t even the fucking reason!</p>



<p>Yep, the real reason was a political one. Turns out the new designer works for Jaguar Range Rover, and they wanted him on the team. The client, knowing they&#8217;d have to fork over a chunk of dough for the abrupt severance if they couldn&#8217;t somehow point the finger at us, so they fabricate some vague reasons for it.</p>



<p>I mean, I wasn&#8217;t that mad, their hands were tied after all. My wife also runs a startup and I know the massive pressure they get when the suits start poking their noses in the business. Still, the way they handled it was kind of a dick move, seeing how it could&#8217;ve affected my performance assessment at my company (which didn&#8217;t happen thankfully, my bosses kind of saw right through it, that&#8217;s why I like it here. That&#8217;s a life tip right there, only work for people who are smarter than you).</p>



<p>But anyway, it&#8217;s all behind now. Tbh I sorta forgot about it already, but it resurfaced once again in my yearly performance review so I had to vent it.</p>



<p>#rantover</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/02/looking-back-at-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is &#8220;Creativity&#8221;?</title>
		<link>/2020/04/what-is-creativity/</link>
					<comments>/2020/04/what-is-creativity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 10:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what is creativity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So one of my fellow designer recently posted this: Basically one of his client saidthis Using repetitive layout patterns in app design in order to improve learnability is just an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So one of my fellow designer recently posted this:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://i.imgur.com/XbF0i5k.png" alt="XbF0i5k" title="What is &quot;Creativity&quot;? 4"></p>
<p>Basically one of his client saidthis</p>
<blockquote><p>Using repetitive layout patterns in app design in order to improve learnability is just an excuse for being lazy at creativity.</p></blockquote>
<p>And that raises an interesting question (for me anyway): just what is &#8220;Creativity&#8221;, anyway?</p>
<p>Now I&#8217;m not talking about its literal definition, we all have our own intepretation of what it is. I&#8217;m talking about how we &#8211; the people in the design community &#8211; perceive it.</p>
<p>Graphic designers, product designers, illustrators, painters, UI/UX designers, visual GFX artists, game artists etc. we&#8217;re own thrown into the same blanket category: &#8220;Creatives&#8221; they call us. But that word, Creativity, it&#8217;s not the same thing for all of us.</p>
<p>For graphic designers, illustrators, painters&#8230;Creativity is a goal, the ultimate destination where you want to take your creations</p>
<p>For UI/UX/Product designers&#8230;Creativity is a tool, and as with any other tool, you only wield it to serve a purpose. And in our case, that purpose is Usability.</p>
<p>Think about it, if you&#8217;re an artists, a painter, your work doesn&#8217;t really serve anyone else but your own creators, and those who follow their visions. The ultimate validation of your works is its creativity.</p>
<p>But as a product designer, your work serves other purposes</p>
<p>In conclusion, to answer the question: is it bad if your creation is not super innovative?</p>
<p>I&#8217;d say it depends on the purpose of your creation.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s for show, then yes</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s for use, then no.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/04/what-is-creativity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Go to school, kids, or you&#8217;ll end up working for Freenom</title>
		<link>/2019/11/go-to-school-kids-or-youll-end-up-working-for-freenom/</link>
					<comments>/2019/11/go-to-school-kids-or-youll-end-up-working-for-freenom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 23:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumbfucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumbshit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freenom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid fuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Look at this motherfucking piece of stupid shit We don&#8217;t see any content on your website, so it must be fraud -Some dumbshit execs at Freenom No, you can&#8217;t make [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Look at this motherfucking piece of stupid shit</p>
<blockquote><p>We don&#8217;t see any content on your website, so it must be fraud</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>-Some dumbshit execs at Freenom</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>No, you can&#8217;t make this shit up. You can actually read about it in this article on their piss poor excuse of a knowledgebase <a href="https://my.freenom.com/knowledgebase.php?action=displayarticle&amp;id=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/11/go-to-school-kids-or-youll-end-up-working-for-freenom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Good bye Mr. Snowball</title>
		<link>/2019/11/good-bye-mr-snowball/</link>
					<comments>/2019/11/good-bye-mr-snowball/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 03:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealing with death]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div  class="tatsu-g8paoxhh5f733nf5 tatsu-section  tatsu-bg-overlay   tatsu-clearfix" data-title=""  data-headerscheme="background--dark"><div class='tatsu-section-pad clearfix' data-padding='{"d":"15px 0px 15px 0px"}' data-padding-top='15px'><div class="tatsu-row-wrap  tatsu-wrap tatsu-row-one-col tatsu-row-has-one-cols tatsu-medium-gutter tatsu-reg-cols  tatsu-clearfix tatsu-g8paoxhh7l56koa6" ><div  class="tatsu-row " ><div  class="tatsu-column  tatsu-bg-overlay tatsu-one-col tatsu-column-image-none tatsu-column-effect-none  tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19"  data-parallax-speed="0" style=""><div class="tatsu-column-inner " ><div class="tatsu-column-pad-wrap"><div class="tatsu-column-pad" ><div  class="tatsu-module tatsu-text-block-wrap tatsu-g8paoxhhbgee4h8h  "><div class="tatsu-text-inner tatsu-align-center  clearfix" ><style>.tatsu-g8paoxhhbgee4h8h.tatsu-text-block-wrap .tatsu-text-inner{width: 100%;text-align: left;}</style></p>
<p>2005:<br />
Wasn&#8217;t particularly an eventful year.<br />
Lots of things hasn&#8217;t happened yet.<br />
The first iPhone wasn&#8217;t due for another 2 years.<br />
I wasn&#8217;t even in college, just a kid fresh out of High School.<br />
And yet one thing made that year particularly memorable to me, to all of my family.<br />
This guy right here.<br />
I still remember vividly the day he came into our lives, such tiny little creature, with piercing blue eyes. So small and yet nothing seems to be scaring him. Footsteps, loud noises, nothing could even make him turn his head.<br />
(We soon found out that&#8217;s because he&#8217;s completely, utterly deaf<span class="_47e3 _5mfr" title="smile emoticon"><img decoding="async" class="img" role="presentation" src="https://static.xx.fbcdn.net/images/emoji.php/v9/t4c/1/16/1f642.png" alt="1f642" width="16" height="16" title="Good bye Mr. Snowball 5"><span class="_7oe" aria-hidden="true"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></span></span> which is also why he never had a formal name, because nobody could&#8217;ve called him. He was simply known as &#8220;The Snowball&#8221;)<br />
Then he&#8217;d proceed to spend the next 14 years of his life brightening up our days, without fail.<br />
Today is no different really. After spending most of the days being awesome, he took a hearty meal from his favorite bow, went back to his favorite box, took a nap, and decided not to wake up again.<br />
Today is a beautiful autumn day. I guess if you could choose how and when to go, today is as good as any.<br />
Still, it&#8217;s never easy losing a friend who was with you for almost half your life.</p>
<p>2005-2019<br />
Rest in peace buddy, you may have left our lives, but you will never leave our hearts.</p>
<p></div></div><div  class="justified-gallery-outer-wrap oshine-module  tatsu-O9fUbFcDA   " ><div class=" justified-gallery-inner-wrap " data-action="get_be_justified_gallery_with_pagination" data-paged="1" data-source='{"source":"selected","account_name":"","count":"","col":"two","masonry":1}' data-images-array="6222,6223,6224,6225,6226,6227,6228" data-items-per-load="9" data-hover-style="style2-hover" data-image-grayscale="c_to_bw" data-image-effect="none" data-thumb-overlay-color="" data-grad-style-color="" data-like-button="0" data-disable-overlay="0" ><div class=" justified-gallery clickable clearfix be-photoswipe-gallery init-slide-top" data-gutter-width="3" data-image-height="200"  ><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fb.jpg" data-size="2048x1365" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fb.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="1365" width="2048" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fb-1000x667.jpg" title="Fb" alt="fb"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6222"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0002.jpg" data-size="3000x2000" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0002.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="2000" width="3000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0002-1000x667.jpg" title="IMG 0002" alt="IMG 0002"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6223"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0016.jpg" data-size="2000x1333" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0016.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="1333" width="2000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0016-1000x667.jpg" title="IMG 0016" alt="IMG 0016"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6224"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_9998.jpg" data-size="2000x3000" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_9998.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="3000" width="2000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_9998-1000x1500.jpg" title="IMG 9998" alt="IMG 9998"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6225"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7537.jpg" data-size="3000x2000" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7537.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="2000" width="3000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7537-1000x667.jpg" title="LH2A7537" alt="LH2A7537"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6226"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7543.jpg" data-size="3000x2000" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7543.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="2000" width="3000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/LH2A7543-1000x667.jpg" title="LH2A7543" alt="LH2A7543"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6227"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div><div class="element be-hoverlay not-wide style2-hover c_to_bw jg-entry-visible"><div class="element-inner none-effect"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/photo_2019-11-06_23-12-34.jpg" data-size="960x1280" data-href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/photo_2019-11-06_23-12-34.jpg" class="thumb-wrap" title="" data-><div class="flip-img-wrap"><img class="thumb-img" height="1280" width="960" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/photo_2019-11-06_23-12-34.jpg" title="Photo 2019 11 06 23 12 34" alt="photo 2019 11 06 23 12 34"></div><div class="thumb-overlay"><div class="thumb-bg" ><div class="thumb-title-wrap display-table-cell vertical-align-middle align-center fadeIn animated"></div></div></div></a><div class="gallery-like  like-button-wrap"><a href="#" class="custom-like-button no-liked" data-post-id="6228"><i class="font-icon icon-icon_heart"></i><span>0</span></a></div></div><div class="caption"></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image" ></div></div><div class="tatsu-overlay tatsu-column-overlay tatsu-animate-none" ></div></div><style>.tatsu-row > .tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19.tatsu-column{width: 100%;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19.tatsu-column > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-column-overlay{mix-blend-mode: normal;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-left-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh9i1w9q19 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-right-divider{z-index: 9999;}</style></div></div></div></div><div class="tatsu-section-background-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-section-background" ></div></div><div class="tatsu-overlay tatsu-section-overlay"></div><style>.tatsu-g8paoxhh5f733nf5 .tatsu-section-pad{padding: 15px 0px 15px 0px;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh5f733nf5 > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh5f733nf5 > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-g8paoxhh5f733nf5 .tatsu-section-overlay{mix-blend-mode: normal;}</style></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/11/good-bye-mr-snowball/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>K岷t th煤c m瓢峄i nm</title>
		<link>/2019/09/ket-thuc-muoi-nam/</link>
					<comments>/2019/09/ket-thuc-muoi-nam/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 02:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[H么m nay t矛nh c峄 l么i quy峄n h峄 chi岷u ra, ph谩t hi峄n 茫 岷n ngy h岷t h岷n, t峄 nhi锚n nh峄 l岷i c谩i ngy ny 煤ng 10 nm v峄 tr瓢峄c, c岷m gi谩c [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>H么m nay t矛nh c峄 l么i quy峄n h峄 chi岷u ra, ph谩t hi峄n 茫 岷n ngy h岷t h岷n, t峄 nhi锚n nh峄 l岷i c谩i ngy ny 煤ng 10 nm v峄 tr瓢峄c, c岷m gi谩c h芒n hoan khi nh岷n 瓢峄c n贸 v岷n c貌n nh瓢 in.</p>
<p>C贸 nhi峄u th峄 t峄 c谩ch 芒y m峄t th岷p k峄 m m矛nh ko c貌n c贸 th峄 nh峄 n峄i n峄a, nh瓢ng cu峄n h峄 chi岷u ny th矛 m矛nh v岷n nh峄 nh瓢 in, v矛 b峄i c岷nh 岷c bi峄t m m矛nh nh岷n 瓢峄c n贸.</p>
<p>10 nm tr瓢峄c l k峄 ni峄m 60 nm thnh l岷p h茫ng hng kh么ng JetBlue, b峄n n贸 d芒n ch啤i offer 1 c谩i deal cho ph茅p m矛nh mua 1 c谩i v茅 $600 c贸 th峄 bay 岷n b岷t c峄 s芒n bay no m JetBlue c贸 ho岷t 峄ng trong l茫nh th峄 US. V 贸 l kh峄i 岷u c峄a t岷t c岷, chuy岷n &#8216;road trip&#8217; 岷u ti锚n trong cu峄c 峄i, chuy岷n i m峄 mang 岷u 贸c 岷u ti锚n. (tr瓢峄c th峄i i峄m 贸 m矛nh thu峄c lo岷i hardcore introvert, c岷 th谩ng ch峄 c贸 岷n tr瓢峄ng r峄i v峄 nh ch啤i game, ko ra kh峄i nh, n岷u kh么ng c贸 b ch峄 l么i i chuy岷n i ny ch岷c gi峄 m矛nh v岷n ti岷p t峄c lesor l岷m).</p>
<p><span id="more-6097"></span></p>
<p>V岷n nh峄 l峄ch tr矛nh nm 贸 i qua bao nhi锚u thnh ph峄, t峄 NY 岷n Orlando (l岷n 岷u 瓢峄c i Disney World), 岷n Hollywood, 岷n Santa Monica, r峄i pha ng茫 峄 峄i c峄a b ch峄 峄 Lombard St., SF lm su媒t n峄a ph岷i i c岷p c峄u. Nh瓢ng ch瓢a c贸 l煤c no chuy岷n i g岷n v峄i vi峄c k岷t th煤c s峄m nh瓢 s峄 ki峄n x岷y ra 峄 Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Theo l峄ch tr矛nh, 2 ch峄 em r峄i Orlando, FL bay t峄i Puerto Rico vo ngy 13/09/2009. 煤ng l ngy 13 c贸 kh谩c, tuy ko ph岷i th峄 6 (Ch峄 Nh岷t n岷u m矛nh nh峄 ko l岷m). Thnh ph峄 th矛 th峄i ti岷t d峄 ch峄u ng岷t ng芒y, nh瓢ng v峄 t峄i KS ch瓢a k峄p lm g矛 茫 b峄 m峄t c谩i t谩t vo m岷t khi ph谩t hi峄n ra 峄 qu锚n 1 c谩i t煤i tr锚n taxi, trong 岷y c贸 1 c谩i h峄 chi岷u v c谩i netbook c峄a m矛nh (back when netbooks are still a thing).</p>
<p>Ph岷n ti岷p theo th矛 m矛nh ko nh峄 r玫 l岷m, ch岷c do panic attack, m panic c农ng ph岷i th么i, l岷n 岷u i roadtrip m 茫 g岷p ph岷i ph峄t nh瓢 v岷y. Ch峄 nh峄 m啤 h峄 c岷nh g峄i v峄 b谩o v峄i b峄 m岷 m b峄 m岷ng t茅 t谩t, ch岷c 峄ng t峄 San Juan v岷n nghe 瓢峄c ti岷ng t峄 New York v峄ng xu峄ng. R峄i m岷y ngy ti岷p theo 2 ch峄 em b峄 h岷t l峄ch tr矛nh i ch啤i 峄 ng峄i l峄 峄 s芒n bay t矛m xem c贸 g岷p l岷i th岷ng taxi 岷y kh么ng. M kh峄, b锚n Puerto Rico th峄i ti峄n Uber n贸 v岷n hnh theo ki峄u nhi峄u h茫ng taxi v岷n hnh d瓢峄i c霉ng 1 banner, kh谩c nhau m峄i c谩i ng k媒. C谩ch duy nh岷t 峄 ID c谩i taxi 岷y l t峄 ho谩 啤n taxi, m c谩i ho谩 啤n 岷y n贸 峄 lu么n trong c谩i t煤i m矛nh m岷t m峄i au. N贸i chung th峄i ti峄n taxi c么ng ngh峄 c贸 nhi峄u th峄 b岷t c岷p m b芒y gi峄 ch煤ng ta taken for granted l岷m.</p>
<p>M vi峄c m岷t h峄 chi岷u b矛nh th瓢峄ng v峄n 茫 th峄n, vi峄c m岷t h峄 chi岷u khi i roadtrip 峄 岷t Puerto Rico n贸 c貌n th峄n h啤n. Th么ng th瓢峄ng khi bay l瓢峄n trong 50 bang ch铆nh th峄c c峄a m岷o (bao g峄m c岷 c谩c bang v峄n kh么ng d铆nh li峄n vo &#8220;Hoa k峄 岷i l峄c&#8221; nh瓢 Alaska hay Hawaii) th矛 m矛nh v峄n ch峄 c岷n show ID ch峄 ko c岷n h峄 chi岷u. Nh瓢ng th岷ng PR n贸 o谩i om 峄 ch峄, tuy n贸 l l茫nh th峄 ch瓢a h峄p nh岷t c峄a US (unincorporated land of the United States), nh瓢ng khi di chuy峄n gi峄a PR v 岷i l峄c th矛 v岷n c岷n c贸 h峄 chi岷u (c贸 VISA US v I-84). Ngoi ra, v矛 m矛nh i v茅 anniversary c峄a Jet Blue n锚n n贸 c贸 1 requirements l n岷u y锚u c岷u hu峄/峄i chuy岷n th矛 ph岷i th么ng b谩o tr瓢峄c 3 ngy n岷u ko s岷 b峄 ph岷t th锚m m岷y trm 么 贸, ko nh峄 l岷m. M itinerary c峄a m矛nh 峄 PR c贸 3 ngy n锚n ko th峄 no b谩o k峄p, phen ny x谩c 峄nh b峄 ph岷t cho tung 铆t r峄i.</p>
<p>峄 c贸 th峄 ti岷p t峄c chuy岷n roadtrip ny, c谩ch duy nh岷t l ph岷i lm l岷i 瓢峄c quy峄n h峄 chi岷u V xin 瓢峄c VISA US V chuy峄n 瓢峄c quy峄n h峄 chi岷u 岷y 岷n Puerto Rico trong 2 ngy. M峄t nhi峄m v峄 c贸 th峄 n贸i l b岷t kh岷 thi. V岷y m m岷 m矛nh lm 瓢峄c 岷y. M岷 m矛nh tuy 谩c kh岷u nh瓢ng ph岷i c么ng nh岷n l煤c c岷n thi岷t v岷n l superhuman. T岷t t岷n t岷t vi峄c xin ph谩i on lm ho岷 t峄c l岷i 1 cu峄n h峄 chi岷u, r峄i phi sang ph谩i on US nn n峄 n贸 c岷p cho 1 c谩i VISA, v ra FedEx ho岷 t峄c xu峄ng PR, t岷t c岷 m岷 m矛nh ch峄 lm trong c贸 峄c 1 ngy!</p>
<p>Tuy ko th峄 no xin l岷i 瓢峄c c谩i form I-84 v矛 c谩i 贸 ch峄 h岷i quan m峄i c岷p 瓢峄c, nh瓢ng b锚n c峄a kh岷u PR v岷n cho qua sau khi m矛nh show 瓢峄c h矛nh screenshot c峄a t岷m I-84 c农 (thanks god for the cloud).</p>
<p>Anyway, 贸 l c芒u chuy峄n c峄a h啤n 10 nm tr瓢峄c v峄 vi峄c t岷i sao m矛nh s峄 h峄u 瓢峄c 1 trong nh峄ng cu峄n h峄 chi岷u &#8220;c峄a 峄c&#8221; t岷i Vi峄t Nam m c贸 n啤i c岷p 峄 n瓢峄c ngoi. H峄i m峄i v峄 i lm th岷 ng芒n hng c贸 b岷n teller c貌n h峄n nhi锚n h峄i m矛nh &#8220;Anh l Vi峄t ki峄u 岷?&#8221; trong khi c岷m trong tay quy峄n h峄 chi岷u VN v峄 xanh c峄a m矛nh, ch峄 v矛 c谩i d貌ng 贸.</p>
<p>Nh谩y m岷t 1 ph谩t m 茫 h岷t h岷n r峄i, nhanh th岷t. Ng岷m l岷i trong 10 nm 岷y m矛nh ch瓢a g岷n th锚m 瓢峄c nhi峄u trang vo cu峄n s峄 c峄a m矛nh ngoi c谩i visa US v i Loan. C貌n l岷i ton c谩c con d岷u c峄a c谩c n瓢峄c trong khu v峄c 么ng Nam .</p>
<p>10 nm, tr么i qua nhanh nh瓢 1 gi岷c m峄ng. T峄 h峄i cu峄c 峄i m矛nh c貌n 瓢峄c m岷y l岷n 10 nm n峄a, v m矛nh s岷 lm 瓢峄c g矛.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/09/ket-thuc-muoi-nam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moving on from bad services</title>
		<link>/2019/08/moving-on-from-bad-services/</link>
					<comments>/2019/08/moving-on-from-bad-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 03:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m an loyal person, once I use a service, I tend to stick with it, even if the service quality goes down, I&#8217;d tolerate it. But there comes a time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m an loyal person, once I use a service, I tend to stick with it, even if the service quality goes down, I&#8217;d tolerate it.</p>
<p>But there comes a time when man must put his foot down and say &#8220;That&#8217;s enough!&#8221;</p>
<p>So the last month I&#8217;ve decided to switch services for many things that I&#8217;ve used for a long time:</p>
<h2>Mobile carrier:</h2>
<p>I&#8217;ve been a faithful<strong>Mobifone</strong> user for as long as I have a cell phone, dating back all the way to 2005 I think when I got my first phone (a Motorola L7, I could still remember it vividly). But this month I&#8217;ve decided to switch to<strong>Viettel</strong>, they&#8217;ve come a long way, and is just better overall.</p>
<h2>Internet Service Provider:</h2>
<p>There aren&#8217;t really any different between the major ISPs here in Vietnam, every year they get pretty much the same amount of dreadful downtime. But recently, <strong>FPT</strong> was discovered to have shady pricing schemes with their customers, so now once again I&#8217;m sticking with <strong>Viettel</strong> as my main ISP.</p>
<p>Banking:</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure most of you can relate to this one, you use<strong>Vietcombank,</strong>realize their service is completely and utter shit, but you still have to use them anyway, because your company pays your salary through them. It&#8217;s a common issue, nobody likes them, but everybody uses them, so they don&#8217;t give a shit. They burden their customers with all kinds of bullshit fees, treating them as if they&#8217;re a burden. Well, this last month my company managed an incredible feat: <strong>breaking free from Vietcombank</strong>. (or as I&#8217;d like to call it, relieving 2000+ accounts from their burden).</p>
<p>We switched to <strong>HSBC</strong> because it&#8217;s convenient for my UK-based firm, but really, their internet banking is a completely different beast. I&#8217;ve never since that kind of UX since, well, kindergarten. But that&#8217;s a story for another day.</p>
<h2>Remote Desktop:</h2>
<p>Just by uttering the word Remote Desktop you probably would&#8217;ve guessed what I&#8217;ve been using for the last 10 years, yes it was<strong>TeamViewer</strong>, I&#8217;ve been using them ever since their first days, when nobody even know who they are. While I&#8217;ve never been a paid customer, I believe I&#8217;d paid my due by being a super active evangelist. I&#8217;ve installed TeamViewer for everyone I know who might need help, I&#8217;ve showed a handful of people how to use it. I played my part in building up the popularity that they have today, and what do I get in return?</p>
<p>A big FUCK YOU is what.</p>
<p>My account was flagged as a &#8216;potentially commercial account&#8217;, and connection time was limited to 30 seconds. Yes you read that right, 30 fucking seconds! Holy mother fucking shit</p>
<p>Luckily, like with all things in life, eventually something better will come along and kick the shit out of it. In this case, that thing is called &#8220;AnyDesk&#8221;. Not only does it work so much more reliably, it also doesn&#8217;t leave a fucking nagging message after every session. Seriously, that thing annoyed the shit out of me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/08/moving-on-from-bad-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How it feels going back to freelancing in Vietnam</title>
		<link>/2019/03/how-it-feels-going-back-to-freelancing-in-vietnam/</link>
					<comments>/2019/03/how-it-feels-going-back-to-freelancing-in-vietnam/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam V农]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(artwork by DeeKay@Dribbble)]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(artwork by DeeKay@Dribbble)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/03/how-it-feels-going-back-to-freelancing-in-vietnam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
