<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>fuckautodesk &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/fuckautodesk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 03:56:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>fuckautodesk &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Houdini 17 Banshee &#8211; Sneak Peek</title>
		<link>/2018/10/houdini-17-banshee-sneak-peek/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/houdini-17-banshee-sneak-peek/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 03:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuckautodesk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[houdini]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the description: Houdini 17 includes a wealth of new features, including a GPU-accelerated multisolver for cloth, hair, soft bodies and grains, a new white water solver, a material-based destruction [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the description:</p>
<blockquote><p>Houdini 17 includes a wealth of new features, including a GPU-accelerated multisolver for cloth, hair, soft bodies and grains, a new white water solver, a material-based destruction framework, facial autorigs, fullbody IK, enhanced animation and modeling workflows, UV autoseaming, GLTF I/O, gamedev tools and much more.</p></blockquote>
<p>You guys hear that, GPU-accelerated cloth engine! Looks like we won&#8217;t even need nCloth or Marvelous Designer in the future. I honestly don&#8217;t know how they do it, but every new release blows our friggin&#8217; mind, unlike Maxon&#8217;s releases, which takes a lot of concentration to spot the changes. Don&#8217;t get me wrong I still very much like Cinema4D, releases are still leaps and bounds better than Autodesk&#8217;s bug-ridden products, but it kinda hit a R&amp;D block for a few years now.</p>
<p>As far as Autodesk go, well I guess given their huge market share, they might stay relevant for a few more years, but if you want job security, I&#8217;d suggest to jump on the Houdini bandwagon as soon as possible. Houdini 16.5 has been going stable on my Deepin Linux box on first try, while Autodesk Maya <a href="/2018/08/17/installing-autodesk-maya-2018-update-3-on-deepin-linux-15-6/">took a lot more effort to install</a>, and even by some miracles you manage to get it to run, it wouldn&#8217;t last long, a simple graphic driver update (which is absolutely necessary) would break your installation easily. Face it, a company with decades operating in the industry and billions of dollar in the bank, still couldn&#8217;t get something as simple as that done, then it&#8217;s only a matter of time before people move on to better things.</p>
<p>Get Houdini today! (I&#8217;m not even getting paid for promoting it, it&#8217;s just that the team over at SideFX is just too awesome)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/houdini-17-banshee-sneak-peek/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
