<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>linux &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/linux/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 04:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>linux &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Note to self: how to copy files to Google Cloud VM Instance as Root using WinSCP</title>
		<link>/2019/11/note-to-self-how-to-copy-files-to-google-cloud-vm-instance-as-root-using-winscp/</link>
					<comments>/2019/11/note-to-self-how-to-copy-files-to-google-cloud-vm-instance-as-root-using-winscp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 07:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[centos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[centos 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote root login]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root login]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winscp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you use VPSSIM or any other administration script in your VPS or GC VM Instance, you&#8217;re probably finding yourself unable to copy or modify anything when connecting to your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you use VPSSIM or any other administration script in your VPS or GC VM Instance, you&#8217;re probably finding yourself unable to copy or modify anything when connecting to your server using WinSCP.</p>
<p>The reason is that, by default, your server is configured to only allow key pairing authentication, so in order to login as a regular user, you have to do 2 things. First, enable <em>password authentication</em> and secondly, enable <em>Login as Root</em></p>
<p>To connect as Root, you first need to set a password for your Root user (<code>sudo passwd</code>), then allow logging in remotely as root. To do so, fire up your <code>/etc/ssh/sshd_config</code></p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="shell">nano /etc/ssh/sshd_config</pre>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Add a line in the Authentication section of the file that says <code>PermitRootLogin yes</code>. This line may already exist and be commented out with a &#8220;#&#8221;. In this case, remove the &#8220;#&#8221;.</p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="shell"># Authentication:
#LoginGraceTime 2m
PermitRootLogin yes
#StrictModes yes
#MaxAuthTries 6
#MaxSessions 10</pre>
<p>Scroll down a few lines and change this line:</p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="shell"># To disable tunneled clear text passwords, change to no here!
#PasswordAuthentication yes
#PermitEmptyPasswords no
PasswordAuthentication yes
</pre>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Save the updated <code>/etc/ssh/sshd_config</code> file and restart the SSH server (<code>service sshd restart</code>)</p>
<p>Should be good to go now</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/11/note-to-self-how-to-copy-files-to-google-cloud-vm-instance-as-root-using-winscp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Electron Toolbelt</title>
		<link>/2019/08/my-electron-toolbelt/</link>
					<comments>/2019/08/my-electron-toolbelt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 04:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[css]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronjs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[html]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Love it or hate it, Electron is now an important part of your everyday life. For those who haven&#8217;t heard of it by now, Electron is a software framework that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Love it or hate it, Electron is now an important part of your everyday life. For those who haven&#8217;t heard of it by now, Electron is a software framework that enable developers to create desktop applications using web technologies (HTML, CSS, JS). It garnered a lot of attention in recently years.</p>



<p>Sure, many elitist developers have publicly spoken against it. They argue that their performance is sub par comparing to native applications, even go as far as <a href="https://medium.com/commitlog/electron-is-cancer-b066108e6c32" target="_blank" rel="noopener">calling Electron apps &#8220;web pages&#8221;</a>. In reality, they were correct, and also completely missed the point. What Electron brings to the table isn&#8217;t performance, but availability. Electron massively lowered the barrier-to-entry in desktop software development, and cut the cost of porting applications across platforms to almost nothing at all. Truth is, I think what the elitist developers are so pissed off about is that fact Electron enabled &#8216;lesser devs&#8217; to build beautiful, functional apps that work cross-platform, something that would take decades for them to achieve.</p>



<p>While I can see why the old devs are unhappy with these changes, as an end user I couldn&#8217;t be happier with Electron. It&#8217;s a godsend.</p>



<p>Anyway here&#8217;s my list of Electron-based apps that I couldn&#8217;t live without</p>



<span id="more-6048"></span>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Figma &#8211; Screen Design Tool</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screenshot-2020-04-02-14.15.27.png" alt="Screenshot 2020 04 02 14.15.27" title="My Electron Toolbelt 1"><figcaption>Figma Screenshot</figcaption></figure>



<p>Given that I am a front-end UI designer, this one obviously tops the list. Unlike most other items in this list though, Figma is not just a &#8216;multi-platform alternative&#8217; to its competitors, it&#8217;s actually THE best tool available in its field. And with its recent addition of plugin support, it&#8217;s only getting better</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Visual Studio Code &#8211; General Text Editor</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1024" height="550" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-1024x550.png" alt="image 3" class="wp-image-21595" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-1024x550.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-300x161.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-768x413.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-1536x825.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-93x50.png 93w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-650x349.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-1000x537.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3-50x27.png 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-3.png 1919w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" title="My Electron Toolbelt 2"><figcaption>VS Code screenshot</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Brackets &#8211; HTML/CSS/JS Editor</h3>



<p>To be honest you can just use VS Code for everything Brackets does, but since they&#8217;re both free, why do you have to choose? Sure at its core, it&#8217;s only a text editor, but out of the box it&#8217;s just work so much better for web development. It&#8217;s capable of editing CSS from within the HTML document just like they&#8217;re in-line, and they comes with a neat little server that lets you preview your webpage in real-time using Chrome (you can actually pick elements from Chrome and Brackets will jump to the correct code section, it&#8217;s just like using Code Inspector!)</p>



<p>Update 2021: Adobe killed it :((</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Mattermost &#8211; Team Chat</h3>



<p>Unless you&#8217;re a lone wolf, you&#8217;ll most likely need to use some sort of teamchat for internal communication. Now there&#8217;s plenty of choices in this area, and Slack used to be my go to choice in this field. But ever since I joined r/selfhosted, I&#8217;ve joined the great movement to segregate from big corps data, and now I host my own team chat</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Telegram &#8211; General Messaging</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="577" height="715" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-4.png" alt="image 4" class="wp-image-21596" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-4.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-4-242x300.png 242w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-4-40x50.png 40w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-4-50x62.png 50w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" title="My Electron Toolbelt 3"><figcaption>Telegram screenshot</figcaption></figure>



<p>For general messaging, nothing beats Telegram. It looks and feels consistent across all devices and platforms. Rock solid application.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bootstrap Studio &#8211; Visual HTML Editor using Bootstrap</h3>



<p>This is the odd one among my choices, due to the fact that it&#8217;s not free. If you haven&#8217;t noticed yet, I&#8217;m a sucker for free softwares, and I usually populate my toolbelt with such, not because of some ideology or anything, I&#8217;m just a cheapskate. But once it a while there&#8217;s proprietary softwares that just blow you away. Bootstrap Studio is one of those.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Balena Etcher &#8211; Bootmaker</h3>



<p>Formerly known as only Etcher, this is a USB boot drive creator, which is something I use far more than an average person (I manage like 60+ computers, TeamViewer actually flagged my account as a commercial one). If you&#8217;ve ever used other USB bootmaker like Rufus or YUMI, you&#8217;d understand why Etcher prevail. (hint: it has something with other bootmakers UI looking like garbage)</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Git Kraken</h3>



<p>Git is an amazing version control application, and Github is the best Git service provider out there, and of course, they have their own Github client to manage any repositories you have. But in their infinite wisdom, they&#8217;ve decided to make that application available to Windows and OS X only. Can you imagine it? Official client of the largest open source repositories in the world not being available on Linux? That&#8217;s just bad taste.</p>



<p>Thankfully, we have Git Kraken to fill that void.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fontbase</h3>



<p>Sure when it comes to a font manager, cross-platform isn&#8217;t one of the highest priorities unless you&#8217;re capable of syncing your fonts across platform (ideally anyway, but we have TypeKit for that). Still, Fontba.se is one of my most essential app as a designer, mostly because it allows you to enable/disable folders of font without permanently installing them on your system, avoiding overtaxing your computer, and most importantly it&#8217;s capable of doing that WITHOUT administrative right. If you ever work in a corporate environment with tight security policies, you&#8217;d understand why this is necessary.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Mail Spring</h3>



<p>Yo</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Honorable mentions</h1>



<p class="has-text-align-center">These are also Electron-based apps that I use frequently but didn&#8217;t get added to my crucial list since they are either A. Sloppily implemented or B. Unnecessary</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Skype</h3>



<p>This is one of those apps that you install out of necessity instead of actual usefulness. You use Skype because your client/colleagues/everyone else is using it, not because it&#8217;s a great messaging app. Microsoft made a right decision going Electron with their popular messaging service, but the product was released way too prematurely. So many bugs that sometimes render the app damn near impossible to use. Like c&#8217;mon, I only need to see the last message in a conversation, which was cached, why the fuck do you need to blank out the page while you load previous conversations? Why?</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Tusk</h3>



<p>Tusk is a desktop wrapper for the popular note-taking application Evernote. See, Evernote is one of those service where a simple desktop wrappers actually works better than a full-blown desktop application, mainly because a desktop wrappers does not count toward your 3-device restriction. &#8220;But I could do that myself with Nativefier already though&#8221; -is what you&#8217;re probably thinking. Well, Tusk differ from your average homebrew Nativefier app in that it actually adds some value to Evernote, like the ability to change theme to Dark mode or Sepia mode, and uh, well that&#8217;s about it I guess. All in all if you still use Evernote for some reason, and don&#8217;t know what to choose from dozens of near identical desktop client, go with Tusk.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Xmind</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Postman</h3>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/08/my-electron-toolbelt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My ghetto $40 home cloud server/media center setup</title>
		<link>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/</link>
					<comments>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 04:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awesomeness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDR3 memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fileserver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghetto fileserver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google file stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[megasync]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namvu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network-attached storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q6600]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tonido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vunam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoho Docs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So I have a bunch of old hard drives laying around. About 5-6 different hard drives of various capacities ranging from 1TB to 2TB, not counting the 2.5&#8243; drives. Looking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I have a bunch of old hard drives laying around. About 5-6 different hard drives of various capacities ranging from 1TB to 2TB, not counting the 2.5&#8243; drives. Looking at that pile, naturally the first thing that comes to mind is building a NAS. I was going to get a cheap Buffalo NAS for around $50 but then I realized I&#8217;d also need it to double as a workstation since I do need (I think &#8216;need&#8217; is the right word) a computer in my workshop</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the parts I used:</p>
<p><strong>Hardware Setup:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mobo: Lenovo MTQ45MK <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $15</span></strong> <em>| salvaged from an old ThinkCentre M58, what I like is that unlike most OEM PCs, this mobo actually has 4 RAM slots, making it a lot cheaper to add more memories since 2GB sticks are dirt cheap.</em></p>
<p><strong>CPU: Intel Quad Q6600 <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $8</span></strong> | <em>probably the best bang for the buck CPU you can get for socket 775, a quad-core processor that goes for under $10, with an amazing overclocking head room (not that we are going to be doing any OCing, but it&#8217;s nice the have the option)</em></p>
<p><strong>Memories: (x4) Kingmax 2GB DDR3 1333Mhz <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $4/ea</span></strong> <em>| DDR3 memories are cheaper than dirt these days, plus you most likely have stick or two already lying around somewhere. I already 2 sticks so I only needed to order 2 more. If you want to meet FreeNAS minimum requirements, this is probably the cheapest way get at it, at $16 for 8GB.</em></p>
<p><span id="more-6084"></span></p>
<p><strong>PSU: Dell 350W <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $8</span></strong> | <em>salvaged from my old XPS 8500 tower, its only down size is the very short CPU power cable, but luckily I got a spare extension laying around. I&#8217;d prefer to use the M58&#8217;s 260W if I had it, as that is still more than enough for our usage, but alas I have to make do with what I have.</em></p>
<p><strong>HDDs: 4TB <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. N/A</span></strong> <em>| as mentioned above, the reason we&#8217;re building this server is because I have a lot of old hard drives lying around, including a Hitachi Deskstar 1TB, a Seagate 1.5TB, a Western Digital Green 2TB and a few smaller drives. Many of these already had bad sectors so it&#8217;s not possible to price them correctly. I&#8217;m sure if you&#8217;re building a NAS you must&#8217;ve had a few HDDs laying around already. If not, the price for traditional persistent storage are dirt cheap these days.</em></p>
<p><strong>Case <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE</span></strong> <em>| you could barely call this case a </em></p>
<p><strong>Software setup: </strong></p>
<p><strong>Windows 7 64-bit <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE</span></strong> <em>| this hardware actually is capable of running Win10 but I&#8217;m not a big fan of the telemetry, not because of any ethical reason or anything, I just think any unnecessary services running in the background would consume more energy. If you wondering why I chose Windows instead of Linux, which is the more conventional choice for fileservers, the answer is simple: sync clients. I use a lot of different cloud services, like Google Drive, SugarSync, Mega.nz, Dropbox, Zoho Docs, Tencent Weiyun, Baidu Wangpan&#8230; you name it, I use it. Not all of them have sync clients for anything other than Windows. Sure there&#8217;s workarounds to get it work on Linux for each of them, but I simply don&#8217;t have time to poke around to get them to work. Windows simply plug and play, that&#8217;s what I need.<br />
</em></p>
<p><strong>Tonido Home Server <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE </span></strong><em>| best all around software to setup a home server with remote access. Far easier to setup than NextCloud, Tonido is pretty much plug and play.</em></p>
<p><strong>Google Drive File Stream <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $7</span></strong> <em>| bought a &#8220;lifetime&#8221; Google Drive Unlimited from a shady local school admin, still my best investment to date. I expected it to die after a month or 2. It&#8217;s been 2 years now and still going strong</em></p>
<p>So the setup is like this: this server is going to be my primary fileserver where everything, and I mean ~everything~ convenes. Every file I want to backup, on all of my computer and devices, and my wife&#8217;s, and my sister&#8217;s, and my parents&#8217;, they all can be backed up to this drive and is accessible from every devices we own! You might say it&#8217;s risky having a central file server like this where I don&#8217;t even have a RAID setup in place, what if the drives fail?</p>
<p>Well you aren&#8217;t wrong, this system was not designed to be a safe vault. In fact, most of the drives I use actually have bad sectors so it&#8217;s only a matter of time. That&#8217;s where the sync clients come in! The offsite backup is what makes this setup a true cloud setup. Everything I have will be gradually be backed up to my Google Drive with unlimited storage. All the other sync clients are only there to pull my files to this server. If I want to access my files on Dropbox for example, instead of having to install the sync client on every devices I own, I simply need to open up Tonido, go into the Dropbox folder on my fileserver and they&#8217;re all there. Isn&#8217;t that beautiful?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to install the latest version of NodeJS on MX Linux 18 &#8220;Continuum&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2019/05/how-to-install-the-latest-version-of-nodejs-on-mx-linux-18-continuum/</link>
					<comments>/2019/05/how-to-install-the-latest-version-of-nodejs-on-mx-linux-18-continuum/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 16:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[github]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mx linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mx linux continuum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nodejs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nodesource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[npm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opensource]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recently needed to install a couple of packages using npm on my MX Linux box. Now MX Linux is fantastic distro, but their repos leave a lot to be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently needed to install a couple of packages using npm on my MX Linux box. Now MX Linux is fantastic distro, but their repos leave a lot to be desired.</p>
<p>I basically did a standard <code class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">sudo apt-get install nodejs</code>, I soon realized that this version of node is severely outdated, and thus utterly completely useless, as you can&#8217;t even call <em>npm</em> from the CLI. So I turned online for help, surely someone else must&#8217;ve come up with a working solution.</p>
<p>Turns out, <a href="https://tecadmin.net/install-latest-nodejs-npm-on-linux-mint/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">somebody did</a>.</p>
<p>The problem is, it didn&#8217;t work.</p>
<p>Not on my installation of MX Linux anyway. The script always failed with this message</p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">## Your distribution, identified as "Continuum", is not currently supported, please contact NodeSource at https://github.com/nodesource/distributions/issues if you think this is incorrect or would like your distribution to be considered for support</pre>
<p>This puzzles me a lot because Continuum was clearly listed as one of the supported distributions right inside the script itself. So I turned to Reddit for help, and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MXLinux/comments/brq7bq/installed_nodejs_but_still_unable_to_run_npm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they delivered</a>. It appears that listing Continuum alone wasn&#8217;t enough, you actually need to append <em>MX</em> or <em>mx-linux</em> in front of it to be identified correctly.</p>
<p>So long story short, here&#8217;s the instruction on how to install the latest release of <em>Node.js</em> on <em>MX Linux 18 Continuum</em></p>
<p><span id="more-6051"></span></p>
<h2>Step 1 &#8211; Configure <em>Node.js</em> PPA</h2>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">sudo apt-get install curl software-properties-common
curl -sL https://vnt87.github.io/nodemx/nodesetupmx_12.x | sudo bash -</pre>
<hr />
<h2>Step 2 &#8211; Install N<em>ode.js</em> on MX Linux 18 Continuum</h2>
<p>It should be fairly standard from this point on.</p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">sudo apt-get install nodejs</pre>
<hr />
<h2>Step 3 &#8211; (Optional) Check <em>Node.js</em> and <em>npm</em> version</h2>
<p>Make sure node and its package manager is installed correctly.</p>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">node -v

v12.3.1</pre>
<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="null">npm -v

6.9.0</pre>
<p>You should now have a fully functional installation of Node.js and npm on your computer.</p>
<p>Note that this is for the latest version of node, if you need the LTS version, let me know (or create one yourself from the Reddit thread that I linked).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/05/how-to-install-the-latest-version-of-nodejs-on-mx-linux-18-continuum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zeplin Desktop client for Linux</title>
		<link>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/</link>
					<comments>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 03:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natifier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[native zeplin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeplin linux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As mentioned in one of my previous posts, we now have an excellent tool for screen design to work on right there on Linux. But what about design handoff? With [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As mentioned in one of my <a href="/2018/10/30/installing-figma-client-on-deepin-linux-15-7-desktop/">previous posts,</a> we now have an excellent tool for screen design to work on right there on Linux. But what about design handoff? With Figma, normally you have 2 choices for handoff: one is Avocode, the other is Zeplin. Most people would prefer Zeplin since Avocode is a subscription based abomination. But there&#8217;s one problem for Linux screen designer: Zeplin does not have a desktop client for Linux. Now this isn&#8217;t much of an issue like other softwares because they have a webapp, but you can&#8217;t integrate Figma with the webapp, unfortunately.</p>
<p>After looking around, I realize Zeplin, like many other great web-based apps, was built on top of the execellnt ElectronJS framework, that means porting it is fairly trivial. After murking around, I came up with this, let me know if it works:</p>
<h4><a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1aNEzGFXTPJ8d7UGywEUjsK8XWsa9lw71" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Download zeplin-linux-x64.tar.gz</a></h4>
<p>Made with nativefier</p>
<p>So now that we&#8217;ve managed to make desktop client for both Figma and Linux, it should be trivial to integrate them right? Well not really, turns out the folks over at Figma currently only has the integration option enabled for their Windows and Mac client. If you&#8217;re a designer working on Linux right now, and need Figma &amp; Zeplin integration, consider spamming their support blog for this feature. I mean, we did that hard part, creating the desktop clients for them, right? All they need to do now is enable integration between the 2 apps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/11/zeplin-desktop-client-for-linux/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essential things to get things done in Linux (2019 edition)</title>
		<link>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 04:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gravit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[libreoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietkey linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wps office]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ok I’m gonna give an honest list of the best software to use in each category in MY unbiased experience. What I mean by unbiased is that I will pick [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ok I’m gonna give an honest list of the best software to use in each category in MY unbiased experience. What I mean by unbiased is that I will pick a software base solely on the overall user experience that it provides (functionality AND aesthetic), REGARDLESS of whether it’s Free software or not. Most other list will either be sponsored or heavily biased toward free software, and since there’s only one or two decent software in each category, you’ll end up seeing pretty much the same list over and over again, year in and year out.</p>
<p>It’s not that I don’t support free software, quite the contrary I’m actually a huge supporter of free software (why else would a graphic designer like me use Linux as his primary working platform). But I’m also aware that for a platform like Linux to gain traction in the end-user market, it needs support from software developers. Yes, all of them, even proprietary software. After all, you can only reasonably expect a program to function correctly if the developer behind it has the incentive to make it better.</p>
<p>Onto the list, my choices are based on the following criterias: <strong><b>function</b></strong>, <strong><b>aesthetic</b></strong>, and <strong><b>performance</b></strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><b>Function </b></strong>means it has to get the thing it was designed for done, that’s the baseline.</li>
<li><strong><b>Aesthetic </b></strong>means it has to have a well designed interface. This is, for the longest time, the weakest point in most opensource software. Obviously it’s not as important as Function but IMO still a far more important aspect to software than most people give it credit for. A well design UI/UX will boost your productivity by a wide margin.</li>
<li><strong><b>Performance </b></strong>means the software have to perform at its best on Linux, meaning no emulated Windows or OS X App, VMs are out of the table also. That doesn’t mean the app have to be native, mind you. It’s 2018, I will also gladly choose app created with web technologies like Figma or Vectr, granted that it runs consistently on Linux just as it does on any other platform.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Here we go</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best Linux Distro: Deepin OS</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will tell you about Ubuntu, Mint or Fedora</em></p>
<p>I’ve used quite a lot of different distros in my time. Off the top of my head, I’ve used Ubuntu, Mint, elementaryOS, Majaro, Arch, Fedora, Zorin. You can see there’s no Gentoo, Red Hat or CentOS in my line up. That’s because I’m not a power Linux user, I only choose distros that boast userfriendliness, aimed at the end user, with pretty interfaces. And judging by the criterias, Deepin OS takes the trophy.</p>
<p>I remember some 15-16 years ago, when Vietkey Linux &#8211; the first ‘Vietnamese’ operating system hit the mass. Yes it was simply a reskin of Red Hat, with little change under the hood, but it got me into liking the platform. Back then, the UI of Linux in general, compares to its contemporary counterpart Windows XP, was nothing short of a massive pile of steaming garbage. And then Ubuntu came along with its sweet streamlined interface and Compiz-powered effects. I was completely blown away.</p>
<p>Fast forward 16 years later, when pretty much everything on the market more or less has a good UI, I didn’t expect to get that sensation again, but then I did, when I installed Deepin OS.</p>
<p>To be honest, my expectation for the distro was low, mostly due to my previous experience with a Chinese distro called Red Flag Linux, yes I do realize the irony of the name. But the Deepin experience wasn’t like Red Flag, but more like MIUI. It’s clean, it’s fresh, packed with little touches that indicates there was involvement from real UI/UX/IxD designers. Unlike most Chinese product, Deepin didn’t feel like a copied and pasted product, because it’s not. The overall user experience is very pleasant (except for the setting sidebar, I mean, who brilliant UX designer was it that think people want the settings they’re changing to disappear everytime they click outside the window?)</p>
<p>Overall. I rate this a 10/10, the first time I ever rate a distro this high. Meaning this is a mature product, complete and ready to compete with the likes of Windows and Mac. It’s currently my production platform.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best Office Suite: WPS Office</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will tell you about OpenOffice and LibreOffice.</em></p>
<p>Yet another software from China, by now some people must be think I might be a commie. Well I actually am, but that’s not why I choose WPS Office. I choose it simply because it is THE best office suite for Linux, in every way. LibreOffice is based on OpenOffice, this massive pile of Java code that is both fugly and sluggish. WPS on the other hand is responsive, good looking, has great compatibility (it saves as microsoft file format instead of its own), AND portability (1GB of cloud storage means you can access your file anywhere, anytime instead of worrying about forgetting to hit Ctrl-S.</p>
<p>Overall, the only reason why WPS hadn’t dominate the Linux office world yet is because a lot of people still use Office for idealistic reasons rather than focusing on productivity reason (and also, many people don’t trust Chinese softwares, much less storing sensitive files on their cloud). They are all valid reason, but for me, WPS is the office suite of choice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best raster graphic editor: Krita</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will say it’s the GIMP</em></p>
<p>As one of the longest supporter of the GNU Image Manipulation Program, it makes me sad that the software had lagged so far behind. For a while, it was considered a Photoshop ‘alternative’, and some still calls it that, but we all know that’s not the case anymore. While the offering from Adobe has received a crapton of new features over the years due to their massive resources, our beloved GIMP still look and feel like the same guy we use 10 years ago. Even the image editor that comes with K-Office: Krita beat the GIMP in every aspects. Maybe it’s time we let it rest.</p>
<p>Krita on the other hands had seen massive improvements over the years. It now has the UI of a professional image editor, something that the GIMP couldn’t accomplished after decades of development.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best vector graphic editor: Gravit Designer</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will say it’s Inkscape</em></p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, Inkscape is a heavy contender. The gap between Inkscape and AI is far smaller than the gap between GIMP and PS. And yet I still have to choose a web based app over it due to its ease of use, its beautiful aesthetic, and portability (storing files on the cloud ftw!)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><b></b><strong><b>Best screen design tool: Figma</b></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><em>List that are Freeassed will have no idea what it is.</em></p>
<p>Screen design tool is a new software segment, one that didn’t exist just a few years ago. I myself didn’t even know of their existence until Adobe released their Adobe XD a few years ago. Yes I know that was already pretty late since Adobe themselves were late to the game, XD hit the market as a response to Sketch’s popularity. Like I said in a previous blog post, I believe that despite its massive popularity, Sketch’s days are numbered, killed by free cross-platform tools like Adobe XD and Figma.</p>
<p>Figma is not the best screen design tool on Linux, nor it is the best screen design tool on the web. It is THE best screen design tool, across all platform, period. Everything you do, you do directly on the cloud, you don’t ever have to worry about hitting Ctrl+S ever again!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Best 3D software package</strong></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/essential-things-to-get-things-done-in-linux-2019-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Install Unity3D on Deepin Linux 15.6</title>
		<link>/2018/08/install-unity3d-on-deepin-linux-15-6/</link>
					<comments>/2018/08/install-unity3d-on-deepin-linux-15-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 11:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity installer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity linux installer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity3d]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div  class="tatsu-fuge7utpbuecmm12 tatsu-section    tatsu-clearfix" data-title=""  data-headerscheme="background--dark"><div class='tatsu-section-pad clearfix' data-padding='{"d":"15px 0px 15px 0px"}' data-padding-top='15px'><div class="tatsu-row-wrap  tatsu-wrap tatsu-row-one-col tatsu-row-has-one-cols tatsu-medium-gutter tatsu-reg-cols  tatsu-clearfix tatsu-fuge7utpmzewvoqk" ><div  class="tatsu-row " ><div  class="tatsu-column  tatsu-column-no-bg tatsu-one-col tatsu-column-image- tatsu-column-effect-  tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9" data-animation="fadeIn"   data-parallax-speed="0" style=""><div class="tatsu-column-inner " ><div class="tatsu-column-pad-wrap"><div class="tatsu-column-pad" ><div  class="tatsu-module tatsu-text-block-wrap tatsu-fuge7utq8ga66mrk  "><div class="tatsu-text-inner tatsu-align-center  clearfix" data-animation="fadeIn"  ><style>.tatsu-fuge7utq8ga66mrk.tatsu-text-block-wrap .tatsu-text-inner{width: 100%;}</style><p></p><p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://i.imgur.com/DoQnK01.png" width="1918" height="1012" alt="DoQnK01" title="Install Unity3D on Deepin Linux 15.6 4"></p><p>Okay this post is nothing but a link, which is this one:</p><p></p><p></p><p><a href="https://beta.unity3d.com/download/cc814e4d942d/public_download.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Download Unity 2017.4.9f1</a> (latest version as of this post (yeah I know, it&#8217;s almost 2019 but I guess Unity isn&#8217;t big enough to hire a real Linux maintainer)</p><p></p><p></p><p>Seriously, that link should&#8217;ve been the first result when you google &#8216;Unity3D Installer for Linux&#8217;, but google thinks you want to read a blog post instead. Typical third rate search engine.</p><p></p></div></div></div></div><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image" ></div></div></div><style>.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9.tatsu-column > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-column-overlay{mix-blend-mode: none;}.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-left-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9 > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-right-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuge7utpxjsi0b9.tatsu-column{transform: translate3d(0px,0px, 0);}</style></div></div></div></div><div class="tatsu-section-background-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-section-background" ></div></div><style>.tatsu-fuge7utpbuecmm12 .tatsu-section-pad{padding: 15px 0px 15px 0px;}.tatsu-fuge7utpbuecmm12.tatsu-section{margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;}.tatsu-fuge7utpbuecmm12 > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuge7utpbuecmm12 > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}</style></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/install-unity3d-on-deepin-linux-15-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Installing Autodesk Mudbox 2018 on Deepin Linux 15.6</title>
		<link>/2018/08/installing-autodesk-mudbox-2018-on-deepin-linux-15-6/</link>
					<comments>/2018/08/installing-autodesk-mudbox-2018-on-deepin-linux-15-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 10:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autodesk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mudbox 2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working on linux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div  class="tatsu-fuf8c529yqdtczfi tatsu-section    tatsu-clearfix" data-title=""  data-headerscheme="background--dark"><div class='tatsu-section-pad clearfix' data-padding='{"d":"15px 0px 15px 0px"}' data-padding-top='15px'><div class="tatsu-row-wrap  tatsu-wrap tatsu-row-one-col tatsu-row-has-one-cols tatsu-medium-gutter tatsu-reg-cols  tatsu-clearfix tatsu-fuf8c52a7h824i3g" ><div  class="tatsu-row " ><div  class="tatsu-column  tatsu-column-no-bg tatsu-one-col tatsu-column-image- tatsu-column-effect-  tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a" data-animation="fadeIn"   data-parallax-speed="0" style=""><div class="tatsu-column-inner " ><div class="tatsu-column-pad-wrap"><div class="tatsu-column-pad" ><div  class="tatsu-module tatsu-text-block-wrap tatsu-fuf8c52amrbmz6qn  "><div class="tatsu-text-inner tatsu-align-center  clearfix" data-animation="fadeIn"  ><style>.tatsu-fuf8c52amrbmz6qn.tatsu-text-block-wrap .tatsu-text-inner{width: 100%;}</style>

<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1918" height="1012" class="wp-image-3830" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DeepinScreenshot_mudbox_20180819174722.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DeepinScreenshot_mudbox_20180819174722.png 1918w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DeepinScreenshot_mudbox_20180819174722-300x158.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DeepinScreenshot_mudbox_20180819174722-768x405.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DeepinScreenshot_mudbox_20180819174722-1024x540.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1918px) 100vw, 1918px" title="Installing Autodesk Mudbox 2018 on Deepin Linux 15.6 5">
<figcaption>Mudbox 2018 running on Deepin Linux 15.6</figcaption>
</figure>



<p class="has-drop-cap">Following my <a href="/2018/08/17/installing-autodesk-maya-2018-update-3-on-deepin-linux-15-6/">previous post on how to install Maya 2018 on Linux</a>, today I&#8217;m gonna be installing Mudbox 2018. But instead of forcing you to go through all that craps, I&#8217;m just going to condense the steps into this simple script. Just run this thing and be done with it. (If you need the installer, you can grab it <a href="http://trial2.autodesk.com/NET18SWDLD/2018/MBXPRO/ESD/Autodesk_Mudbox_2018_EFGJ_Linux64.tgz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">directly from Autodesk</a>, for some reasons they try to hide the 2018 version from my account, only showing 2017 and older, I had to dig up half the server to hunt down this link) <span id="more-3829"></span></p>



<pre class="EnlighterJSRAW" data-enlighter-language="shell">#!/bin/bash
#2018 Nam Vu aka envigraphy
#envigraphy@gmail.com

# This script assumes that you have downloaded your copy of the mudbox.tgz to /home/namvu/Downloads/Autodesk/$MUDBOXINSTALL, and that it is named: Autodesk_Mudbox_2018_EFGJ_Linux64.tgz


#Setup a few vars (Change the file name here if your .tgz file has a different name)
#Also change the PRODUCTID if you are not installing Mudbox 2018 (for example, Mudbox 2016 has a PRODUCTID 498G1)
export MUDBOXINSTALL='Mudbox_2018_Installer'
export INSTALLFILE="Autodesk_Mudbox_2018_EFGJ_Linux64.tgz"
export RPM_INSTALL_PREFIX=/usr
export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/opt/Autodesk/Adlm/R12/lib64/
PRODUCTID="498J1"


if [ `whoami` != root ]; then
    echo Please run this script using sudo
    echo Just type “sudo !!”
    exit
fi
#Check for 64-bit arch
if [/bin/uname -m != x86_64]; then
    echo Mudbox will only run on 64-bit linux. 
    echo Please install a 64-bit Linux distro and try again.
    exit
fi


#Install Message
echo "You’re about to install Autodesk Mudbox 2018"
echo ""
echo "Do you wish to continue [Y/n]?"
read RESPONSE
case "$RESPONSE" in
  n*|N*)
  echo "Install Terminated"
  exit 0;
esac

#Get serial number
echo "Enter the serial number"
read SERIALNUMBER
echo ""

export INSTALLDIR=/home/namvu/Downloads/Autodesk/$MUDBOXINSTALL
cd $INSTALLDIR
chmod -R 777 $INSTALLDIR

# Install Dependencies
apt-get install csh tcsh libaudiofile-dev libglw1-mesa elfutils gamin libglw1-mesa-dev mesa-utils xfstt ttf-liberation ttf-mscorefonts-installer xfonts-100dpi xfonts-75dpi alien libgstreamer0.10-dev libgstreamer-plugins-base0.10-dev libtiff5 openssl
sleep 3s


# Extract Mudbox Install Files
tar xvf $INSTALLDIR/$INSTALLFILE
# Convert rpms to debs
for i in $INSTALLDIR/*.rpm; do alien -cv $i; done
sleep 2s
#install the debs
dpkg -i --force-overwrite $INSTALLDIR/*.deb

#Required for license to install
cp libadlmPIT.so.11 /usr/lib/libadlmPIT.so.11
cp libadlmutil.so.11 /usr/lib/libadlmutil.so.11
ln -s /usr/lib/libadlmPIT.so.11 /usr/lib/libadlmPIT.so
ln -s /usr/lib/libadlmutil.so.11 /usr/lib/libadlmutil.so

# License Setup:
echo -e 'MUDBOX_LICENSE=unlimitednMUDBOX_LICENSE_METHOD=standalone' &gt; /usr/autodesk/mudbox2018/bin/License.env

/usr/autodesk/mudbox2018/bin/adlmreg -i S $PRODUCTID $PRODUCTID 2018.0.0.F $SERIALNUMBER /var/opt/Autodesk/Adlm/Mudbox2018/MudboxConfig.pit
 
# symbolic links:
# libtiff
ln -s /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.5.2.0 /usr/lib/libtiff.so.3
sleep 2s

# check to see if libtiff.so.3 exists
if [ ! -e /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.3 ]; then
  if [ ! -e /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.5 ]; then
    echo "=========================================================================================="
    echo "Cannot locate libtiff.so.3 OR libtiff.so.5"
    echo "You will need to find a version of libtiff somewhere and make a symlink from /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.3 to point to that file."
    echo "Normally libtiff libraries live in /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/"
    echo "So, go to that dir and see if you can find a version of libtiff.so."
    echo "Then make a symlink to that file by using the command:"
    echo "sudo ln -s  /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.3"
    echo "For example: sudo ln -s /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.5 /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.3"
    echo "Good luck!"
    echo "=========================================================================================="
  else
    ln -s /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.5 /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libtiff.so.3
  fi
fi
 
#Everything should work now... 
echo "Installation Complete."
echo ""
echo "Start Mudbox Now?"
read RUNNOW
case "$RUNNOW" in
  n*|N*)
  echo "You can run mudbox any time by typing mudbox into the terminal"
  exit 0;
esac
mudbox</pre>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

</div></div></div></div><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image" ></div></div></div><style>.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a.tatsu-column > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-column-overlay{mix-blend-mode: none;}.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-left-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-right-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuf8c52afc2zil5a.tatsu-column{transform: translate3d(0px,0px, 0);}</style></div></div></div></div><div class="tatsu-section-background-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-section-background" ></div></div><style>.tatsu-fuf8c529yqdtczfi .tatsu-section-pad{padding: 15px 0px 15px 0px;}.tatsu-fuf8c529yqdtczfi.tatsu-section{margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;}.tatsu-fuf8c529yqdtczfi > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fuf8c529yqdtczfi > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}</style></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/installing-autodesk-mudbox-2018-on-deepin-linux-15-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working on Linux: Restore Firefox&#8217;s normal behavior</title>
		<link>/2018/08/working-on-linux-restore-firefoxs-normal-behavior/</link>
					<comments>/2018/08/working-on-linux-restore-firefoxs-normal-behavior/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 07:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div  class="tatsu-fugjj0q5vd3h8zhg tatsu-section    tatsu-clearfix" data-title=""  data-headerscheme="background--dark"><div class='tatsu-section-pad clearfix' data-padding='{"d":"15px 0px 15px 0px"}' data-padding-top='15px'><div class="tatsu-row-wrap  tatsu-wrap tatsu-row-one-col tatsu-row-has-one-cols tatsu-medium-gutter tatsu-reg-cols  tatsu-clearfix tatsu-fugjj0q643adc6fb" ><div  class="tatsu-row " ><div  class="tatsu-column  tatsu-column-no-bg tatsu-one-col tatsu-column-image- tatsu-column-effect-  tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy" data-animation="fadeIn"   data-parallax-speed="0" style=""><div class="tatsu-column-inner " ><div class="tatsu-column-pad-wrap"><div class="tatsu-column-pad" ><div  class="tatsu-module tatsu-text-block-wrap tatsu-fugjj0q6ixkey8k  "><div class="tatsu-text-inner tatsu-align-center  clearfix" data-animation="fadeIn"  ><style>.tatsu-fugjj0q6ixkey8k.tatsu-text-block-wrap .tatsu-text-inner{width: 100%;}</style><p></p><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://cdn.pcsteps.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Configure-Firefox-without-About-Config-with-an-Add-on-01.png" width="600" height="340" alt="Configure Firefox without About Config with an Add on 01" title="Working on Linux: Restore Firefox&#039;s normal behavior 6"></p><p>One of my main gripe when switching from Windows to Linux is that my favorite web browser Firefox doesn&#8217;t behave exactly the same way it does on Windows. Specifically, 2 things that bother me the most are:</p><p></p><p></p><ul><li>The Backspace button doesn&#8217;t go back to the previous page</li><li>Clicking on the url address bar doesn&#8217;t automatically highlight the entire line.</li></ul><p></p><p></p><p>Fortunately, it&#8217;s possible to change those behaviors simply by fiddling around with the settings a little bit. You&#8217;d want to go to your <strong><em>about:config </em></strong>page and change the following values:</p><p></p><p></p><ul><li>Find <strong>browser.backspace_action</strong> and set the value to <strong>0</strong> (default is 2 or something). This will make the backspace button behave as it does in Windows.</li><li>Find <strong>browser.urlbar.clickSelectAll </strong>and set the value to <strong>True</strong></li></ul><p></p><p></p><p>And that&#8217;s about it. Personally I can&#8217;t understand why the developer would choose to keep these little annoyances. If it was just for a versions or two then we could accept it as bug but it&#8217;s been many years since these behaviors were implemented. The fact they&#8217;re still there mean that they are intended. Maybe they were made by Mozilla devs who are actually Microsoft moles who want to low-key diminish the user experience in Linux, I guess we&#8217;ll probably never know.</p><p></p></div></div></div></div><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-column-bg-image" ></div></div></div><style>.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy.tatsu-column > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-column-overlay{mix-blend-mode: none;}.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-left-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy > .tatsu-column-inner > .tatsu-right-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fugjj0q6btau6ooy.tatsu-column{transform: translate3d(0px,0px, 0);}</style></div></div></div></div><div class="tatsu-section-background-wrap"><div class = "tatsu-section-background" ></div></div><style>.tatsu-fugjj0q5vd3h8zhg .tatsu-section-pad{padding: 15px 0px 15px 0px;}.tatsu-fugjj0q5vd3h8zhg.tatsu-section{margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;}.tatsu-fugjj0q5vd3h8zhg > .tatsu-bottom-divider{z-index: 9999;}.tatsu-fugjj0q5vd3h8zhg > .tatsu-top-divider{z-index: 9999;}</style></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/working-on-linux-restore-firefoxs-normal-behavior/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
