<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>namvu &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/namvu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Powered by Google Cloud Compute</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 04:31:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-namvu_512-150x150.png</url>
	<title>namvu &#8211; Nam Vu Personal Site</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>My ghetto $40 home cloud server/media center setup</title>
		<link>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/</link>
					<comments>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 04:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awesomeness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDR3 memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fileserver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghetto fileserver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google file stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[megasync]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namvu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network-attached storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q6600]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tonido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vunam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoho Docs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So I have a bunch of old hard drives laying around. About 5-6 different hard drives of various capacities ranging from 1TB to 2TB, not counting the 2.5&#8243; drives. Looking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I have a bunch of old hard drives laying around. About 5-6 different hard drives of various capacities ranging from 1TB to 2TB, not counting the 2.5&#8243; drives. Looking at that pile, naturally the first thing that comes to mind is building a NAS. I was going to get a cheap Buffalo NAS for around $50 but then I realized I&#8217;d also need it to double as a workstation since I do need (I think &#8216;need&#8217; is the right word) a computer in my workshop</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the parts I used:</p>
<p><strong>Hardware Setup:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mobo: Lenovo MTQ45MK <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $15</span></strong> <em>| salvaged from an old ThinkCentre M58, what I like is that unlike most OEM PCs, this mobo actually has 4 RAM slots, making it a lot cheaper to add more memories since 2GB sticks are dirt cheap.</em></p>
<p><strong>CPU: Intel Quad Q6600 <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $8</span></strong> | <em>probably the best bang for the buck CPU you can get for socket 775, a quad-core processor that goes for under $10, with an amazing overclocking head room (not that we are going to be doing any OCing, but it&#8217;s nice the have the option)</em></p>
<p><strong>Memories: (x4) Kingmax 2GB DDR3 1333Mhz <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $4/ea</span></strong> <em>| DDR3 memories are cheaper than dirt these days, plus you most likely have stick or two already lying around somewhere. I already 2 sticks so I only needed to order 2 more. If you want to meet FreeNAS minimum requirements, this is probably the cheapest way get at it, at $16 for 8GB.</em></p>
<p><span id="more-6084"></span></p>
<p><strong>PSU: Dell 350W <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $8</span></strong> | <em>salvaged from my old XPS 8500 tower, its only down size is the very short CPU power cable, but luckily I got a spare extension laying around. I&#8217;d prefer to use the M58&#8217;s 260W if I had it, as that is still more than enough for our usage, but alas I have to make do with what I have.</em></p>
<p><strong>HDDs: 4TB <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. N/A</span></strong> <em>| as mentioned above, the reason we&#8217;re building this server is because I have a lot of old hard drives lying around, including a Hitachi Deskstar 1TB, a Seagate 1.5TB, a Western Digital Green 2TB and a few smaller drives. Many of these already had bad sectors so it&#8217;s not possible to price them correctly. I&#8217;m sure if you&#8217;re building a NAS you must&#8217;ve had a few HDDs laying around already. If not, the price for traditional persistent storage are dirt cheap these days.</em></p>
<p><strong>Case <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE</span></strong> <em>| you could barely call this case a </em></p>
<p><strong>Software setup: </strong></p>
<p><strong>Windows 7 64-bit <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE</span></strong> <em>| this hardware actually is capable of running Win10 but I&#8217;m not a big fan of the telemetry, not because of any ethical reason or anything, I just think any unnecessary services running in the background would consume more energy. If you wondering why I chose Windows instead of Linux, which is the more conventional choice for fileservers, the answer is simple: sync clients. I use a lot of different cloud services, like Google Drive, SugarSync, Mega.nz, Dropbox, Zoho Docs, Tencent Weiyun, Baidu Wangpan&#8230; you name it, I use it. Not all of them have sync clients for anything other than Windows. Sure there&#8217;s workarounds to get it work on Linux for each of them, but I simply don&#8217;t have time to poke around to get them to work. Windows simply plug and play, that&#8217;s what I need.<br />
</em></p>
<p><strong>Tonido Home Server <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. FREE </span></strong><em>| best all around software to setup a home server with remote access. Far easier to setup than NextCloud, Tonido is pretty much plug and play.</em></p>
<p><strong>Google Drive File Stream <span style="color: #99cc00;">-est. $7</span></strong> <em>| bought a &#8220;lifetime&#8221; Google Drive Unlimited from a shady local school admin, still my best investment to date. I expected it to die after a month or 2. It&#8217;s been 2 years now and still going strong</em></p>
<p>So the setup is like this: this server is going to be my primary fileserver where everything, and I mean ~everything~ convenes. Every file I want to backup, on all of my computer and devices, and my wife&#8217;s, and my sister&#8217;s, and my parents&#8217;, they all can be backed up to this drive and is accessible from every devices we own! You might say it&#8217;s risky having a central file server like this where I don&#8217;t even have a RAID setup in place, what if the drives fail?</p>
<p>Well you aren&#8217;t wrong, this system was not designed to be a safe vault. In fact, most of the drives I use actually have bad sectors so it&#8217;s only a matter of time. That&#8217;s where the sync clients come in! The offsite backup is what makes this setup a true cloud setup. Everything I have will be gradually be backed up to my Google Drive with unlimited storage. All the other sync clients are only there to pull my files to this server. If I want to access my files on Dropbox for example, instead of having to install the sync client on every devices I own, I simply need to open up Tonido, go into the Dropbox folder on my fileserver and they&#8217;re all there. Isn&#8217;t that beautiful?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/08/my-ghetto-40-home-cloud-server-media-center-setup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Sketch will die in 2019</title>
		<link>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Randomness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe xd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comparison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namvu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screen design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma. If you’re a screen designer of any calibre, surely you’ve heard of at least one of these tools. They’re currently the 3 biggest players in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma. If you’re a screen designer of any calibre, surely you’ve heard of at least one of these tools. They’re currently the 3 biggest players in the screen design tool arena.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sketch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Features: being the oldest tool means it has a very healthy ecosystem with a plethora of plugins</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Cons</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Availability: being a Mac exclusive app means it’s only a matter of time before it’s erased from the market.</p>
<p>&#8211; Speed: Sketch is snappy when it comes to opening a file, but viewport stability decreases drastically when navigating around a large project.</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: like every other Mac apps, this shit cost money. If you’re a solo creator, this app is currently more expensive than the other 2 combined times infinity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Adobe XD:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Adobe Ecosystem: being tied to the biggest creativity toolset on the market is a huge!</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: it used to cost money, but it’s free now (undoubted in an effort to accelerate the construction of Sketch’s coffin)</p>
<p>&#8211; Availability: Adobe has a bit more advantage over Sketch in term of platform availability, given that it works on both Windows and OS X. A common misconception is that the majority of the design community works on OS X, that’s only true in North America and Europe. If you count globally, you’ll see that most companies operating in the outsourcing sector (India, APAC) still uses Windows as the primary operating system. Some statistics currently put Sketch at over 70% dominance, but if you count the actual product output (which is huge in the outsourcing sector), I’d suspect that number would drop to somewhere around 30%.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Cons</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Adobe Ecosystem: yes, this is both a pro and con for this nifty little app. Being part of a giant company like Adobe certainly has its perk, while we know Adobe has the resources needed to make Adobe a thing, whether or not those resources are allocated correctly is a different story. We all know there’s very little innovation left going on at Adobe, having dominated the market for so long. They’ve also killed off fantastic tools like Freehand and (gasp!) Fireworks!</p>
<p>&#8211; Availability consistency: apart from the fact that there’s still no client on Linux (which is not a huge deal, I say this as a designer who uses Linux, I know there’s not that many of us).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Figma:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Pros</em>:</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8211; Availability: Figma is the champion when it comes to platform availability. This tool is built with WebGL, with desktop wrapper for desktop use (like Slack). That means it works everywhere as long as you have a web browser (currently it’s THE screen designer of choice for designer working in Linux)</p>
<p>&#8211; Price: if you’re a solo creator, it’s completely free, there’s no limit on the number of project you can have in your account. They only charge if you want to add more than 2 editors to your project, which is completely reasonable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/why-sketch-will-die-in-2019/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Discord-like color scheme for Slack</title>
		<link>/2018/08/a-discord-like-color-scheme-for-slack/</link>
					<comments>/2018/08/a-discord-like-color-scheme-for-slack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nam Vũ]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namvu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vunam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love Slack as a productivity chat client (except the ridiculous pricing) but there&#8217;s one thing I think it could use some improvement, its color scheme. Looking at Slack after [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class="aligncenter" src="https://i.imgur.com/2S1pnL1.png" alt="2S1pnL1" width="1152" height="816" title="A Discord-like color scheme for Slack 2"></p>
<p>I love Slack as a productivity chat client (except the ridiculous pricing) but there&#8217;s one thing I think it could use some improvement, its color scheme. Looking at Slack after coming over from Discord is like looking directly at the sun. Slack does allow you to change the color scheme of the sidebar, but the main part that you look at, you can only change via loading a custom css via their <em>ssb-interop.js</em> file. So here&#8217;s how you do it:</p>
<p><span id="more-3934"></span></p>
<p>Find your Slack&#8217;s application directory.</p>
<ul>
<li>Windows: <code>%homepath%\AppData\Local\slack\</code></li>
<li>Mac: <code>/Applications/Slack.app/Contents/</code></li>
<li>Linux: <code>/usr/lib/slack/</code> (Debian-based)</li>
</ul>
<p>Open up the most recent version (3.3.0 for me) and open <code>resources\app.asar.unpacked\src\static\ssb-interop.js</code> and add this at the very bottom</p>
<pre>document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', function() {
 $.ajax({
   url: 'https://raw.githubusercontent.com/antroxx/slackstheme4EB/master/theme_05.css',
   success: function(css) {
     $("&lt;style&gt;&lt;/style&gt;").appendTo('head').html(css);
   }
 });
});</pre>
<p>Then proceed to Slack setting and use the following colors for your side bar: <code>#2f3136,#3f4145,#7b8d96,#FFFFFF,#2f3136,#ffffff,#242526,#323436</code></p>
<p>And there you have it <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/a-discord-like-color-scheme-for-slack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
